<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Empath Confessions</title><description>A candid look at what it's like to be an empath, clairsentient, claircognizant, and an INFJ - sharing my experiences and tips</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Empath Confessions</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.19</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 23:43:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>BRB!</title><description>I will be taking a break this week, but will return next Tuesday evening with an Empath 101 article!
I want to take this opportunity to thank everyone that is currently reading!
As I am not paying for any advertising, I am relying solely on word of mouth and social media to gain exposure... </description><link>http://localhost:2368/brb-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9c94f6c7630e2294972da2</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/9---BRB.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/9---BRB.png" alt="BRB!"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be taking a break (from posting an article, anyway) this week, but will return next Tuesday evening with an &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empath 101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; article!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take this opportunity to thank everyone that is currently reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; paying for any advertising, I am relying solely on word of mouth and social media to gain exposure. To block spam, I have added moderating to comments within the blog and Facebook group. The original intent is to prevent any kind of &amp;quot;garbage&amp;quot; from getting involved, and not meant to frustrate or deter any readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While (understandably, I get it!) it's awkward to follow along and engage when no one else appears to be, I would like to invite fans to get involved. I have seen a great amount of people that come across and like the blog, as well as my social media accounts and their posts, but see not nearly as many people are following. I only wish to bring this up in hopes of personally reaching out and saying: &lt;em&gt;if my blog is of interest or help to you, please feel free to connect with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow and stay connected on any of these social media accounts:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Facebook:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/empathconfessions/"&gt;www.facebook.com/empathconfessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Instagram:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/empathconfessions/"&gt;www.instagram.com/empathconfessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pinterest board:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/ashleydtilson1/empath-confessions/"&gt;www.pinterest.com/ashleyt/empath-confessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of you have taken the opportunity to reach out to me to ask if I would offer a reading. I thank you greatly for this experience, and your reactions and feedback have helped me even more than you may know (at first, I wasn't sure if I could give a reading to someone I've never met or spoken to, but - &lt;strong&gt;wow&lt;/strong&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am slowly working towards launching my website for readings and coaching, I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; currently doing this to gain experience. Anyone else that is intrigued can feel free to contact me (through whatever venue suits best - you can check my &lt;a href="http://empathconfessions.com/static/about-me/"&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt; page for my email address). My readings are purely Intuition-based, but I also use and incorporate tarot cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently maintaining this blog (and it's social media accounts) alongside my full-time job and home (family) life. While I wouldn't dare complain about the amount of work needed to do all that, I must admit I wish I had more time to dedicate to this. It is my honest hope that as my blog grows, I can gain the experience and exposure needed to turn these hobbies (writing and giving readings) into my new full-time career. Until then, I kindly ask everyone to bare with my response time (but know that I at least follow-up and make arrangements the same day), but know that I welcome all inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I welcome fans to reach out personally, or at least connect, as I would like to create a relationship. I look forward to the chance to give back to you, and plan to start offering promotions to subscribers/followers in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession - Overcoming Obstacles</title><description>As much as I want to share my weight loss story with those that have questions or are looking for advice, I also want to share this story for it’s core lesson: the ability to overcome an obstacle.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-confession-obstacles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9604d4c7630e2294972d8f</guid><category>Empath</category><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 02:20:38 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/8---Confession-2.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/8---Confession-2.png" alt="A Confession - Overcoming Obstacles"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as I want to share my weight loss story with those that have questions or are looking for advice, I also want to share this story for it’s core lesson: the ability to overcome an obstacle. After what seemed like rock bottom for me mentally, I looked at my life and saw that I wanted to change things - more importantly, who I am. Severing ties with that which I no longer wanted to be a part of, I came to a point of realizing that it was crucial to also make some necessary changes on myself. One big thing that stood out for me, as it is also the image of something I don’t want to become, was my appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life/style saw that I was never a skinny person: I hit puberty at a young age, I had depression &amp;amp; anxiety growing up, I ate whatever I wanted to deal with stress, and I went off into the adult world with no concept of how to eat properly (or any understanding of the damage I had already been, and would continue to be, doing). While routine check-up’s with the Doctor always indicated I was overweight, the word “obese” was never used – and it was never discussed further, so I thought nothing of my weight. But as many would agree – there comes an age when you start to realize that your metabolism is not the same as it used to be, and that you start to feel generally unhealthy when consuming too many bad foods/drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my twenties, I had my try at losing weight on many occasions. I was never athletic or involved in sports, and thanks to an old spinal injury I also don’t last long with a workout schedule – which makes things difficult and more discouraging for me.  Diet plans such as low-calorie and low-carb were the easiest methods for me, but only resulted in me losing 20 – 25 lbs. over the course of months, and then not being able to lose more. Repeatedly being stuck at my plateau (always at 150 lbs.) threw me back into a state of depression, and I actually started to believe I was meant to be this size, and meant to be someone who struggled (with weight). Before long, I would drop the diet in an attempt to get my self-esteem back after feeling like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once went to an annual check-up and weighed in around 180 lbs. – this was my first wake-up call that I was actually bigger than I should be. Even though I had already dieted before this point, I never saw it as more than a means to shed some pounds (and not as a big and permanent change). Despite still not having an idea of what weight I should be, I knew I needed to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. Truthfully, I’m still unsure if this contributed at all to my personal revelation, but it definitely gave me the understanding I finally needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without reiterating too much from &lt;a href="http://empathconfessions.com/static/my-discovery/"&gt;My Discovery&lt;/a&gt;: there was one morning when I woke up and as if I had a revelatory dream, I had decided I needed to change everything about my life. While (admittedly) some of these changes involved removing people from my life that were a bad influence, I saw it in myself to also take the steps necessary to ensure that I also never turn into that kind of person. For me, my weight easily registered as a major factor… granted, that I could actually change it. Seeing this as one of my top obstacles in life, I knew it would be a lot of hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reasoning is for making your change, you should ultimately be doing it for yourself. While I looked to what it was I didn’t want to be as my “motivational image”, I knew I was doing it so I would be happier with myself – with how I looked and felt, and how much of a difference that makes in all aspects of life. I knew this was going to be one of the hardest things I would do (as I was aiming to get under 130 lbs.), and that it would only work if I stick with it, and change my lifestyle for good. As I maintain time and time again: &lt;strong&gt;determination&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;persevere&lt;/strong&gt; is really where the credit is due in my achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often ask me what my secret is, or what pill I took. Most assume I’ve been taking diet supplements and was involved in some intensive regime, but it’s actually much more simple than most realize. One of the first things I put out there is one of the fact’s that I’ve learned for myself: if you’re stressed out and not happy with your life, a lot of effort can make a very small difference. Sort out what you need to so that you’re in the right frame of mind; I knew that stress would cause me to rush to junk/fast food (and/or overeat) and impede the motivation required, so I eliminated as many stressors as I could beforehand. In the end, changing my lifestyle was the real change made when I lost weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to finding natural remedies or solutions to issues I had needed medication for, I started to pay more attention to what I ate. I did as much research as possible, including the science behind diet plans and food. As with any obstacle, I wanted to be fully informed and prepared before I started the plan. Doing this allowed me to create my own plan, which I’m happy to share for those looking for advice. Just keep in mind that no matter what happens, and even no matter what the obstacle, you have to continue to reinforce the thought to not give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My weight loss (which was a total of over 50 lbs.) took me roughly a year from beginning to end. Having said that, there is no end to the changes adapted in order to maintain this weight – having worked so hard to get to a weight I haven’t been at since I was a teenager, I could never allow myself to go back. Cutting out junk/fast and processed foods is just one practice I’ve learned to adopt permanently, and is something that can make a big difference on it’s own. Using an app to budget the amount of calories I need (based on weight, etc.), and eating balanced meals* that fit within that, was the strictest I’ve had to be on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I saw this whole process as more of a lifestyle change, I was able to have fun with it. I still had days along the way where I wanted to give up - namely the period when I was stuck at 150 lbs. yet again – but I reminded myself that it just takes time and &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt;. While I did do workout routines and yoga classes off and on in the beginning, my one consistent was actually the neighbourhood retreat I took every morning; I would queue up some music that made me feel good, put on my headphones, and went out for a walk. This 20-30 minute stroll isn’t even the intent of exercise, but is still better than nothing (and is very rejuvenating for the soul).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you that there was anything more significant to the process than what I have already shared. I kept at it, and months later I saw the results I thought to be impossible. For months I didn’t fit into any clothes and, as it made no sense to buy any while I was still losing weight, it took a year to finally get a new wardrobe. Someone whose closet used to be filled with L’s and XL’s is now filled with S’s and XS’s. I never thought I would see such a day (I would’ve been happy to be a M!), but it’s all the proof I need that I can do anything I put my mind to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While very different from my other posts, I want to share this information in hopes of inspiring anyone else like me that has struggled with the issue. I thought it to be impossible, but came to realize that is only my mind choosing to make it fail. Like everything else in life, it takes work and commitment to cement the end results you want. No matter what it is you’re trying to achieve, know that it can be possible as long as you’re determined and willing to follow through with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* My meals included protein shakes (with VegeGreens, and using Almond milk), and homemade meals consisting of a protein (ex: skinless chicken breast) and salad / vegetables (try to stay green), sometimes with a small serving of long grain rice. Beverages were restricted to water and green tea, while I also consumed 64 oz of cranwater (pure Cranberry and water) per day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - Learning Curve</title><description>In the beginning, simply paying attention to sudden thoughts &amp; emotions, and following the signs (questions and instincts) was enough to finally see what I’m capable of.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-learning-curve/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8e2590c7630e2294972d84</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/7---Empath-101-2.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/7---Empath-101-2.jpg" alt="Empath 101 - Learning Curve"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, simply paying attention to sudden thoughts &amp;amp; emotions, and following the signs (questions and instincts) was enough to finally see what I’m capable of. As I began to speak up more, not only did I find I was I getting reassurance on my suspicions, but also that those with personal issues would immediately open up to me. I naturally counsel as I’ve already felt their mood and have some insight as to what it is and how to comfort/remedy it; following through with this action has given me further reassurance in my ability. With practicing all of this over time I suddenly realized that not only was I able to control it, I was also finally confident that I am my genuine self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure how to do this, I can suggest a simple tactic that’s taken right from my INFJ ways: question and investigate everything. As I did my initial research on what it is to be an empath, I started to sift through my life experiences and saw where others’ emotions and insights determined how I felt (about myself) because I didn’t know better. One of the best ways that I now describe it is that I thought it was normal to “know” others’ thoughts and moods, but not knowing why/what that was caused me to suffer and turn in on myself for many years. So at first I started small, simply keeping to a small group of people I was comfortable with in which I could openly speak. Every time I had a thought or felt an emotion that didn’t register as my own immediate focus or concern, I turned to whoever was in my surroundings and talked to them about it – there was rarely a time I wasn’t able to determine what came from who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds forward and possibly a bit ridiculous (depending on your approach and who you have to work with, mostly), but I can assure you that’s the best way to learn your capabilities for yourself and get affirmation. Having said all that though, there is a cautionary area (“filter”) that I did want to talk about. One too many times now, I’ve dealt with a situation in which I was the recipient of life-altering news that (in all honesty) actually didn’t surprise me and reaffirmed past suspicions. Obviously, I did not reveal any of my thoughts at any point in time; this can be a bit of a burden to carry when it involves those closest to you. The reason? We need to know when not to say something, simply because it would be so critical that actual evidence would be the only grounds to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part, I tend not to reveal these thoughts for more than that reason though: in a way, I also question the (current) validity of it. While time and time again I find most of my unwanted suspicions come true, I also hold onto that sliver of hope that circumstances could change and it wouldn’t be true. Anyone that provides readings likely agrees with me on this: the sometimes over-looked fact is that no matter what answers we provide, there’s always a chance that a split-second decision in a different direction can change the outcome (answer) completely.  Knowing this is true about everything in life, is the real reason why I hold back some of the worst thoughts that I have had. And let’s not even get started on the fact of seeing things that could be, but aren’t acted upon!&lt;br&gt;
With all that being said, I mostly carry this filter with those I care for – unless, of course, their life is in danger. Anytime I have done a reading for someone (no matter their relationship to me), I allow my thoughts to be relayed as I hear them and I don’t censor my final interpretation. I mention this because what I’ve written above does not make sense if you’re trying to make a reputable career doing such… but may still apply in some parts of life. While not the same “filter”, I also have a method for when I’m in crowded places such as the mall, busy stores, or a concert – without doing that, I would “suffer the consequences” of many people. This is your more important weapon, and is what most refer to as Protection or Grounding. There are many methods to be found online and it is something you can learn to do in your own style within a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest, and most important, things I learned for myself early on was to let go of everything I encounter. Carrying such thoughts (such as those unspeakable messages), and having such conversations can take a toll on our energy. Aside from solitude, I began practicing Etheric Cord Cleansing at the end of the day. If you’re unfamiliar with this Cleansing, it’s very simple and is something that only needs a few minutes (you can find many examples online – there’s no one right way; similar to Protection/Grounding). Regardless of what works best for you, the one thing you want to adapt to quickly is learning to listen to your body. Your body (usually) gives you the first indicator of anything that’s wrong, but it’s our ability to recognize and react to it that results in the ultimate outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While important no matter who you are and why, listening to your body helps to add context and help you to get to know yourself. Aside from feeling the emotions and state of someone near you, your body has it’s own way of telling you what to do. Whether it’s your natural reaction to the truth of a person’s thoughts or conversation, speaking the words that you feel and wonder if you should say, or simply your own need to seek safe space and time, your body gives you the indicators you need. After recognizing the cues and identifying them over a period of time, you will be able to develop (and likely even surprise) yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Co-Piloting an Empath - Honesty &amp; Acceptance</title><description>Hopefully if you’re an empath and you’re in a relationship, your significant other at least understands enough to at least respect it. A brief conversation my husband and I had was along the lines of him being a skeptic – he didn’t know what to believe, and he didn’t want to be pushed into it.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/co-piloting-an-empath-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8398e5c7630e2294972d7a</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 02:53:36 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/6---Co-Piloting-2-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/6---Co-Piloting-2-1.png" alt="Co-Piloting an Empath - Honesty &amp; Acceptance"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully if you’re an empath and you’re in a relationship, your significant other at least understands enough to at least respect it. A brief conversation my husband and I had was along the lines of him being a skeptic – he didn’t know what to believe, and he didn’t want to be pushed into it. While curious about some of the readings he see's, my new practices are not imposed on him and take place in another room. For me, there isn’t a problem as long as I’m not criticized or treated differently for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely this conversation will come at some point, even if it’s not intended. If all is well, it will be as understanding as possible. As people that had no religious ties throughout our lives, neither of us had any confidence in the initial explanation; except for the fact that I could now finally explain myself, and that the explanation felt right. For my spouse, he simply accepted that’s what it is and respects my new lifestyle, but does not want to be forcibly involved. Although it would probably be interesting to have a spouse (or friend) with the same hobbies, I don’t think there is a better outcome than to accept &amp;amp; respect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important aspect that we ended up discussing was on the topic of honesty. At this point in time, I’m able to look back at everything and realize (almost as if it were drawn out on a page) times where I had physically picked up on a fib; and the reveal some time later. Because I was unaware of my abilities, I suffered physical ailments as a result of not “seeing” what I was actually interpreting. Now that I know what it is, I had to ask if he was okay to agree to not hide anything from me going forward (alternatively, I would end up pointing it out). Maybe it sounds like a tall order, but as a happily married couple, we decided it shouldn’t even be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only mention that point because I’m sure a lot of others have had to bring this up. Everyone has their own background, relationships, and boundaries, but we come to a point where we realize we do more harm to ourselves by remaining idle with certain situations and people. My husband and I used this chance to better our relationship; it seemed to be no better time to do this than when you start this new chapter of your own life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the significant others out there: I hope you do feel you can accept the new lifestyle as it plays out. Be honest if you can’t, as we can understand why. Having the chance to explain it to him, and how it affects me, seemed to be helpful in his understanding – especially as he noticed how it explains some of my behaviour and past (health) issues. Both sides should realize how this affects the empath – physically, emotionally, and mentally – and recognize how this affects our life. Believe me when I say though: you are in for a magical treat if you’re open to sticking around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acceptance conversation can possibly go another way – which I would hope is not the case for anyone, but is a possibility. For myself, I already decided that I wouldn’t be able to deal with it if it wasn’t accepted. I deemed that necessary as I intended to put my happiness &amp;amp; wellbeing in the front seat for once. I’m not trying to persuade anyone on how you decide it should go, but you’ll want to consider what you think is best for you. Everyone should decide where you stand, and want to decide/learn, and be completely honest about it all. Yes, it will take time, and patience, with (hopefully) understanding. Keeping an open and curious mind is what allowed me to open this door, after all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the newly awakened: you will need some patience and understanding when presenting this information, and be prepared for whatever reaction you may expect to get. Blunt, but true. If the conversation goes well by you, just allow everything to transpire over time. Whatever position you look at it from, a period of adjustment will be almost imminent (skepticism, acceptance, development; whatever the case may be for it.). Even if you’re not in a position to have this conversation, at least consider where you stand and what you would need for your future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may not even seem like an important conversation, but I can’t tell you one other person I’ve met like me that hasn’t ended up losing a relationship or two as a result of their reveal. And whether it’s simply removing yourself from toxic relationships, or worse yet – family &amp;amp; friends that laugh at you, there tends to be a divide surrounding your own discovery. As scary as this time may sound, it is also a necessary string of events that will leave you at peace with yourself; as you later realize how happy you are without that negativity in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter which direction these conversations go, or even who you have it with, I hope you have the chance to do right by yourself by being as honest as you can be. In the end, we realize we’re all too good at picking up others' moods and emotions – we might as well utilize this information for our own personal good, if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Old Soul Issues - Technology</title><description>One of the settings I’ve spent a lot of time in during my journey is nature. As an empath that lives in a city, I sometimes feel overwhelmed just by being in public places.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/old-soul-issues-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a764c0fc3ffd80204eebe1b</guid><category>Old Soul</category><category>Empath</category><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/5---Old-Soul-Issues-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/5---Old-Soul-Issues-1.png" alt="Old Soul Issues - Technology"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the settings I’ve spent a lot of time in during my journey is nature. As an empath that lives in a city, I sometimes feel overwhelmed just by being in public places. Whether it’s encountering people that I can tell have bad thoughts or are careless (or worse: are in pain or need help), or dealing with the stress within a busy grocery store, I find I need time to recharge myself after being around people. Crystals have helped to deal with this, but solitude became a new friend for clearing it up quickly. Another key component though, is connecting with nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past summer I made it a goal to spend a week out in a secluded area – a rented house in a small town where you had to drive for 10 minutes to get to a store. The view was farmland mixed with untouched forest, and the sky at night was so clear that you could see every star in view. As a newly awakened empath, the pure peace and quiet that I felt here was healing on it’s own. Spending most of the day outside just taking in the view, enjoying each moment, while being gentle and honest with myself, brought me clarity and much to think about. So much in fact, that most of my blog ideas were created one afternoon during this trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we need to find our own means to “tap into the universe”, and spending time outdoors is a great way to do it. I originally planned to meditate outside on this trip, but found I didn’t need to as long as I allowed myself to just &lt;strong&gt;be&lt;/strong&gt; outside. I kept myself relaxed, on no schedule, and without thought. That last part was the hard one, but is essentially how I was able to finally receive the clarity I was looking for. In a way, I created my own form of retreat by taking this trip, and recommend doing something along these lines whenever you feel the need to disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disconnection played a big part in the trip and some of the thoughts I had. I knew I could expect an unreliable Wi-fi connection, but did not expect to be out of service range on my cell phone. I took this discovery as a sign to turn off all the electronics for the week. It ended up being during this week that I realized a lot of things about technology’s use in life and how I feel that impacts societal needs and people (and those like myself). I welcome hearing if there’s a differing opinion, but have found this to be a common perception with those I’ve shared this with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I’m going to be honest and say that I’m not a fan of most social media. It serves a great function in connecting people easily, but simply feels like more of an obligation nowadays. As someone that still enjoys handwriting letters to friends in other countries, I still cherish the personal approach when connecting with someone. Perhaps it’s also that I agree a lot of things are better spoken than typed, but I find social media takes away from what it really means to meet with and talk to another person. And let’s not even get started on the dark side of putting yourself online; forget privacy, and forget being in control of what’s expected of you for that reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I slam social media, I’m just one that takes a cautious (albeit somewhat silent) approach to it. With my blog, I’m just being honest about the experiences I know aren’t completely unique to me, but I still expect some hate will come from somewhere. As someone that was in high school when computers and cell phones started to become a necessity, it boggles my mind that newer generations are being raised on it. It has a time and place (always), but I feel like generations are on a decline in common sense and core values due to being babysat by it. I’m not saying this is everyone, but it does seem like fewer kids have the interest and ability in activities beyond technology anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as an adult that owns more than just a cell phone and a laptop, I can attest to how distracting technology is to real life. Thanks to the cell phone, we can be interrupted anytime, anywhere; I don’t think I have to divulge any further on that fact either. Thanks to virtually almost everything becoming digital, people (myself included) are now more than ever becoming victim to their personal information being lost and facing (potential) identity theft. While the Internet is an endless source for information, the fact that absolutely &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt; can be put online should’ve always been an indicator to not rely on it as a sole tool in one’s early development and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is probably the quickest and simplest way that I can summarize the reasons that I believe are the downside to our reliance on technology. And with a progressive and uncertain future, who knows what it will be capable of. When I realized these were my perceptions, I also realized another crucial fact: being so “connected” has subconsciously imposed anxiety (on me). Whether it’s the need to address someone (immediately!) because they can see you online anyways, or having other’s personal woes, distressing and fake news, and negative comments imposed on you, the online world truly has become a driving force in our lives – whether we realize it or not. Having realized this for myself is exactly why I don’t spend a lot of time online, unless I’m doing something productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To each it’s own, as I’m sure there’s varying opinions. But having been on this retreat, forcing myself to turn off everything that “connected me to the world”, made me realize how much of a relief it was to lose those obligations temporarily (and how free I felt for it). I’m actually almost tempted to call them responsibilities instead, as I’m sure many people out there have a reason to feel that way about it. And that just brings me back to my exact point: the actual effect that technology has on our lives, which isn’t all healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to not having to answer to the “obligations” of phone calls, texts, emails, etc., I also didn’t have mind-numbing entertainment to fill my time. Even though particular movies, TV shows, and even video games are a hobby of mine, I don’t enjoy the idea of “wasting so much of my free time” with them. Being forced to spend time in absolute silence with myself was the perfect setting for self-reflection because I could easily get into a meditative state. When I wanted to switch gears, I spent time face-to-face with my husband – an activity that’s become somewhat lost over the years because of our hobbies – and we just &lt;em&gt;talked&lt;/em&gt;. We talked about so much that, even though we’ve been together for more than a decade, we learned new things about each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these revelations, I am sure there are other people out there that don't just agree with anything that I’ve said, but that have probably been in the same position as me. Even though we weren’t having any problems in our marriage, spending the week this way helped to bring us closer together, and showed us what’s important. Before I knew it, I suddenly yearned for a simpler life; knowing that one can survive, and be happy, without being so materialistic and plugged in (all the time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relationships are best reciprocated with spoken words, and touch. Socializing in person – and the process surrounding the act of getting together – makes the memories that we carry. Stories and details are best understood when the tone is also present, which is why it feels so wrong (to me) to primarily communicate digitally with close friends. I don’t expect everyone to agree with me, but this is why I leave my connection to technology within my work hours, when it truly is an obligation of mine. Otherwise, Old Soul me only pick’s up technology to make the social plans – after all, for the amount of time that I will sink into composing messages to someone, I could’ve had a longer and better conversation in person!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession - Working</title><description>As an Intuitive Empath, public places and social situations can be a breeding ground for mixed emotions and revelatory messages. Dealing with these aspects while continuing to interact with others (and maintain our composure, depending) can sometimes be challenging.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-confession-working/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a7278edc3ffd80204eebe0f</guid><category>My Journey</category><category>Empath</category><category>INFJ</category><category>Old Soul</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Niagara---No-Fate-BW-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/Niagara---No-Fate-BW-1.png" alt="A Confession - Working"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an Intuitive Empath, public places and social situations can be a breeding ground for mixed emotions and revelatory messages. Dealing with these aspects while continuing to interact with others (and maintain our composure, depending) can sometimes be challenging. When among close family and friends I at least feel comfortable enough to point out (appropriate) conflicts and offer advice, but that’s not something that everyone wants (or cares) to hear. So when I spend time in environments with strangers, or among those only there for a purpose, I end up feeling drained and out of place from being the silent observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret of mine that I haven’t found happiness in my employment history. Some of this comes from being an INFJ, with the effects of being an empath that ultimately cause me to move on. As an INFJ, I’ve always been a perfectionist that secretly enjoys managing (organizing) things; this has always driven me to learn more by never limiting my interests, always wanting to master every new skill, and always asking the questions to understand how things works. As much of a pro as this is, it serves as a con for us personally – I am my worst critic anytime a mistake happens, but that’s usually why I’m the person that can be counted on to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an INFJ, then I’m sure this has already rang true for you too. Despite wanting a fulfilling and glorious career to put my efforts into, I’ve come to conclude that I can’t find that without creating it for myself (somehow). While being an INFJ has been beneficial to where my career has taken me, the flipside of being an empath has revealed truths to me that I couldn’t tolerate. For me personally, there was nothing worse than working hard for a cause or person/people that actually didn’t care half as much as I did. What’s uneasy to deal with is picking up on lies and injustices within decisions but not being able to say/do anything about it (and sometimes having to carry out the decision myself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with conflicts like the above for a period of time can eventually take a toll. I personally found I could tolerate most things, but always kept a tally on issues that made me want to quit. Another lifelong struggle I’ve had was I wanted to be happy in a “normal” life (a vision I’ve come to question since my discovery) – I tried my hardest by sticking with some things until past the point where it’s unbearable. Deep down, I’ve always just tried until I realized my gut has been telling me I need to move on. After all, a job does not encompass who I am as a person, and it definitely isn’t the most important thing in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first few months of my self-development, I was able to manage working full-time as I was genuinely happy with what I was involved in. With interpreting emotions/messages being new though, I felt I started to see everything for what it really is. I honestly felt optimistic given that I could finally deflect the unexplained stress that would suddenly take me over (how I used to interpret certain messages and emotions in the workplace). Despite knowing this would make me a stronger person, and therefore a strong professional, I started to question what was the best use for my skills and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I was inspired to write on this topic specifically after I had left that job. After a couple months of feeling like I was fighting to stay, I initiated talks to confirm some revelatory fears and then gave my notice. The funny part about it though is that it’s my reaction that sparked the idea to write about it. Even though I’m always quick to be done with whatever I’m &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; with, it’s always an emotional goodbye for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call it what you will as I’m not sure what to pin it on, but there’s always been a part of me that holds guilt for “giving up”. I realize I’m only quoting my negative self-talk on the issue, but nevertheless the thought is there; to which I counter with my need to be happy and safe in what I’m doing. INFJ’s can relate to the struggle involved in these thoughts, and also know that they never truly leave us.  The perfectionist me that has worked through promotions has a hard time with where I’m left now - I wonder what I’ve really worked so long and hard for already, when it’s left me nothing but temporary physical means (finances, strong resume), bad memories and unhappy thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone else out there that’s been here, or is here, I really do hope you can find something that works well for you. If you’ve been here and have found a career that you’re happy and excelling in, I commend you for getting there. I realize it will take work, but I finally have a hope that one day I’ll have my dream job (however that will look). As an INFJ and old soul, the work part doesn’t intimidate me nearly as much as the thought of being stuck where I have to paint on a face. When I realized that putting myself through this period of potential self-destruction only shaped me into more of a bitter person, I took a step back and re-evaluated my personal definition for “priorities”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was away on a personal retreat after my departure, I had a lot of thoughts about what was really important and why. I began to wonder why this “normal” life was so essential to have when it just hasn’t worked out for me. Thoughts about how I use my time, what money is spent on (and perhaps, what not to spend it on), what is really essential for living, and what can be sources of happiness, ended up changing my view on life. I realized that I was limiting myself from being genuine and finding my path by just trying to do what’s expected. This was around the time that I started to get ideas about using my qualities to provide my own services to others. Regardless of my goal of working for myself, I now know that it’s only beneficial to me to take on work that I am interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a lot of trial and error to figure out what roles and environments don’t work for me, but I’m thankful for all of the experience it’s given. Even with working towards aspirations, I’ve decided to stick to working for a temporary agency for now (I won’t have to be in one place too long if it didn’t jive with me). It seems that the best advice is to just follow your heart and do what makes you happy. If there’s anything that I can say I stand by now, it’s exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Co-Piloting an Empath - Comfort</title><description>As a HSP (highly sensitive person), I haven't always been the most stable person to live with, emotionally speaking. Despite knowing that this quality is one that my husband adores about me, I have also seen first-hand how challenging it can be to deal with.  </description><link>http://localhost:2368/co-piloting-an-empath-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a5e5d5c5e01130b9844e262</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 20:27:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/blog3-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/blog3-1.jpg" alt="Co-Piloting an Empath - Comfort"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a HSP (highly sensitive person), I haven't always been the most stable person to live with, emotionally speaking. Despite knowing that this quality is one that my husband adores about me, I have also seen first-hand how challenging it can be to deal with. Whether it’s my occasional explosion when I become overwhelmed/stressed, or simply my inability to let certain things go (I never forget anything of significance!), it’s a quirk that comes with my personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until I discovered what I am that I was able to get this under control. The responsibility of control ultimately has to be put on the empath themselves – discovering if this is who you are, recognizing its effects, and learning how to control &amp;amp; deal with it. With that being said though, it’s never going to be “scotch-free”... because as an empath, we are conduits for other people’s emotions (energy)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this series of articles as my own awakening in my abilities sparked a lot of conversations with my husband. As someone that went through her discovery alone, I wanted to share my thoughts and experiences in the hope that it would bring comfort, understanding, or even help, to anyone that ends up reading. Some topics were in order, with one of the most important being on the subject of “comfort”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even controlled, an empath will occasionally need to verbally vent to release the pent-up emotions they’ve experienced. Hopefully, every empath will at one point have someone understanding that they can occasionally confide in – which helps to serve this purpose. But there are some days that we just only see fit to release it in the comfort of our own home; and more than likely, simply will just only be comfortable to do in the presence of our significant other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are the significant other, know this: If we’re doing this in your company, THIS IS A GOOD THING! If we come home to you but start to unravel and have a need to vent about every negative thought/person/experience from the day/week, just know that we’re able to do so because &lt;strong&gt;we trust you with every fibre of our being&lt;/strong&gt;. This is also not a task that is easily done, so know that it’s literally just something we need to do from time to time to feel better. On a personal level, I also feel like we’re looking for the validation from an outside perspective that what we’ve concluded is not unjustified; hence, &lt;strong&gt;we also trust your judgment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had this conversation with my husband, admittedly it became more of a “what am I supposed to do?” on his part. I was surprised to hear that he felt useless being the listener during these rants – he expressed sincere regret in his inability to be of any help for what troubled me. This saddened me and made me make a statement that brings me to the ultimate point here: “I don’t need you to have the answers or advice, I just want you to listen”. I just want someone that I trust to listen to what I’m feeling and why, and just tell me if I’m ever out of line. After all, I'm just trying to purge the thoughts and emotions that I've picked up on that I can't speak on or do anything about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that is the message I have to pass along to significant others: we don’t need you to have the right advice to our situations, we just appreciate you being there and listening! As long as you care enough to do that, that is enough. And please, for your own sake, don’t take on any of our struggle either – it’s hard enough for us to deal with as it is; and we definitely don’t wish it to be brought upon you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that find that this isn’t the case, give yourself a pat on the back! It’s hard not to resort to this activity at certain times in life. Perhaps you have already found a more effective outlet, which is fantastic. Just remember that sometimes it is okay to verbalize buried emotions! We are still human after all, and we know that it feels better to say what we really want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an empath, the best way to avoid getting to this boiling point is being able to remove yourself from these burdens altogether. I plan to write an article on this, but will say that there are many ways to do so including being honest and forward in your decisions &amp;amp; interactions, letting go of situations that are not your responsibility, etheric cord cleansing, and carrying crystals. If you’re new to some of this, don’t be intimidated, as it will just become a part of your everyday once you start adopting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last piece of advice I gave for situations where I am truly upset and there is nothing anyone can say or do about it: just give me a hug! For empaths, a hug is the most comforting gesture anyone can offer... and I'd be surprised to meet someone who would argue with this much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While this article talks about needing to verbally vent, I am not suggesting that this be a (regular) practice. Wherein a relationship where it's mutually agreed and understood that it's a conversation with the intention to &amp;quot;sound off&amp;quot;, then it can be helpful and sometimes productive - personally, this helped me to process a lot of things during my own awakening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With that being said, I can report that now that I feel I have the thoughts and emotions in my control I have found these events to be very rare. If you're working towards this, then rest-assured that you're able to achieve your own peace in how you react to everything you receive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - The Rundown</title><description>Having done a lot of research to support my own discovery, I was saddened I couldn’t find a complete resource online. What I only found through reading one-off articles and blog posts was what it’s really like to be an empath – </description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-the-rundown/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a556e075e01130b9844e246</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/Rattlesnake---lanscape--edge--2.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/Rattlesnake---lanscape--edge--2.JPG" alt="Empath 101 - The Rundown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having done a lot of research to support my own discovery, I was saddened I couldn’t find a complete resource online. What I only found through reading one-off articles and blog posts was what it’s really like to be an empath – this is the comforting reassurance you’re not alone, and the key identifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using this to identify yourself, note that I am both clairsentient/empath and claircognizant. I do feel that I know what is attributed to each, but admit there are times when those lines are blurred for me. For a while I thought they were one and the same, but research and reflection has shown me my “double whammy” (as I jokingly call it, because it allows me to feel, know and predict what’s happening).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, know that it’s something that’s always been a part of you. Some people take a long time to learn about it, and I believe there are a lot more people out there that just simply don’t realize it (or maybe don’t want to). Secondly, it’s not just about having empathy. While by definition it can sound the same, it is by far a more in-depth experience. Many people have empathy, and we adore those that do, but that does not automatically mean they are an “empath”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be forward with the rough stuff. Because let’s be honest: if you’re an empath, you know you’ve had your days where you’ve called this a curse. The effects are harder when you’re unaware of it, but it’s easy to see what was wrong when you do come to understand it. It may not be true for all, but as some of us tend to be old souls, we sometimes find we get the tougher end of the stick in life (arguably for the sake of experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rough stuff has to do with what you endure as an empath. Before discovering who I was, this resulted in me dealing with a lot of health issues. Relatable or not, the indicator is always in what you experience when you’re around people. For example, my stomach would turn and cramp with pain when I was in a stress-filled environment or conversation. Personal conversations always resulted in me becoming a shoulder to cry on, but left me feeling drained, heavy, and responsible for helping that person.  Uneasy conversations are equally emotional too – leaving you feeling physically uncertain, enraged, cheated, and sometimes, knowing when something or someone is not right. The easiest for me to see and experience is being near someone that’s upset or angry – for me those are more like feeling a dark (sometimes leeching) cloud or a ticking time bomb in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just a few brief ways to describe how it feels, but essentially you know you’re an empath when you know this: you can feel (and I mean &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; feel) other’s emotions. If you’ve ever noticed your mood tends to change with your surroundings, and you know you’re not always “100% you”, then you know why that is. You may have had emotional explosions you can’t explain (you may find you have stressed over issues that aren’t your own; but ultimately involved you), and find you tend to be the “go-to” for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another commonality I realized through conversing with other empaths is that we have a low tolerance for media. Some people (myself included) love movies and TV shows, but have drawn a line. For example: News, in any format, is off limits in my home as I find it stressful to deal with. We can take in news and certain subjects, but know what causes an emotional and mental stir in us. For me, the local evening news just upsets &amp;amp; enrages me, but also makes me want to run out and fix everything that’s wrong. As an empath, upsetting news of any kind has the ability to ruin my mood and the rest of my day, purely based on my lack of being able to change the negative circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could probably go on with many more examples and explanations, but this should be enough to identify with. If you can relate to the experiences above, then you may very well be (or know that you already are) an empath. If I had to give it a nutshell explanation, it would be this: the ability to feel the emotions of others nearby, with the ability to experience other persons’ perspectives when you do converse. Naturally, we’re also good counsellors because the above point allows us to know what to say and how to comfort people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the unease in what we endure, there are some magical moments throughout. There is nothing that feels greater than to be in the presence of someone like-minded, or to spend time with someone that feels trustworthy. And once you understand it, it becomes easier to interpret your experiences, which should help alleviate the physical effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to publish more “how to” articles for empaths, but I encourage you to do your own research if you’re looking for identification. With luck, it won’t take you long to get the affirmation you need. I would also recommend meeting someone alike if you can, as this was what gave me answers initially. Just know that as long as you keep an open mind, and pay attention to the signs, you’ll be on the right path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Note: there are sources that say Clairsentience and Empath are one and the same, and sources that define a difference. I encourage you to look at all resources to decide. While I myself have noted differences between the two, I also identify with both and agree that the two are linked (even if the ability of clairsentience lays dormant). *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>My Discovery</title><description>There was one distinct day where I remember my life started to change. It was as if I woke up one morning and literally thought: “That’s it, things need to change”. What saddened me though was that I had already wasted too much time on the wrong things.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/my-discovery/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4e8fde5e01130b9844e233</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/bloggy.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/bloggy.jpg" alt="My Discovery"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was one distinct day where I remember my life started to change. It was as if I woke up one morning and literally thought: “That’s it, things need to change”. What saddened me though was that I was 27 years old, and started to feel like I had already wasted too much time on the wrong things. I simply wasn’t happy (feeling like a robot going through the daily motions), and I knew life could be better, somehow. Whether it was working jobs I felt undervalued in, or keeping to people that took advantage of my kindness, I was ready to put an end to that me. Despite recognizing there’s always still time to put oneself on a different path, I felt like kicking myself for taking so long to open my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always known I was a sensitive person, but it had always been attributed to suffering from depression and anxiety. Having experienced a lot of trauma &amp;amp; stress before I became an adult, I always assumed this was just my luck of the draw that is life. When I realized I wanted the change, I sought out counselling; I got the clarity and validation I needed on my newfound revelations. It was only now that I started to see things for what they were, and I started to deal with people by being honest, putting myself first, and letting go where appropriate. I won’t lie about it: a lot of people found their way out of my life since my transformation began, due to these motions. And I’m sure that anyone that’s experienced will agree: you sometimes have to get rid of the energies that don’t serve you any good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t much at first, but it was simply a lifestyle change in that regard: getting rid of things that don’t bring me happiness. I had time off from quitting my job and used it to focus on myself – simply taking care of myself, self-help reading, spending time on art, and one big goal that I’d struggled to achieve: lose weight. Dealing with depression/anxiety did cause a bad habit of stress eating for me. I wasn’t huge, but I definitely did not care what I ate and how much I ate. When I got married, I shed my goal weight of 10 lbs. for the dress – but that still put me on the scale for close to 170 lbs.. I had never been able to diet and exercise myself under 150 lbs. (my plateau), so I had always given up. But this time I was determined to persevere and over the course of a year, got myself down to 120 lbs.!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a feat for me. Not only did I do what I thought I couldn’t, it made me feel amazing in so many ways. I think overcoming this obstacle following my “change of heart” gave me the confidence needed to discover my true self. When I was about to turn 30, I looked up and met with an Intuitive Life Coach. Her experience with Angel Readings and Akashic Records piqued an interest in me. Of all things to bring as a question, I (even as a skeptic) wanted to know what I was &lt;strong&gt;meant&lt;/strong&gt; to do with my life. I had recently met with Career Counsellors and taken endless profiling quizzes, but it always pointed me towards the same work I had already done or titles of little interest. I, somewhere deep inside, just knew I was meant to do something specific – what I felt was “my life’s purpose”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I went about the appointment like my usual counselling sessions... but then I started getting some messages that brought more questions: I am a really old soul, I am an empath and claircognizant, and I am meant to help people. At this point in my life, helping people has always been a natural impulse to me, sadly taking over even when I don’t want to. This has been a double-edged sword up until this point as I realized I had already sacrificed a lot for people that I shouldn’t have. Truth is, I want to help, but only those that want to be helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the only thing that rang true in the moment. The rest, although eerily comforting to hear, was some spiritual talk that I didn’t know if I believed. I sat on it, and even consulted another psychic – only to receive the same messages. I started doing research on everything mentioned to me in my consultations. Before long, I realized it explained &lt;strong&gt;a lot of things&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve experienced throughout my life. All my years of depression and anxiety (in some part anyways) was suddenly explained by my ability to pick up others’ thoughts &amp;amp; emotions. Sometimes I never knew why I felt so sick to my stomach so often, and now see it happens when exposed to a stressful situation/person. My ability to predict outcomes and behaviours was also explained; sadly, as much as this has helped my managerial skills, it also serves as a shadow in certain situations. Things ever so slowly made sense after this point, and a couple months later I had my first experience with meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first real try at meditating was attending a guided group meditation led by the same Intuitive Life Coach. I honestly did not know what to expect, but went in with an open mind. My experience ended up being nothing short of indescribable! Not only did I encounter a bird that has since shown up in my dreams and in the physical world, but I also experienced myself in a setting from another perspective. My palms and my third eye felt on fire and sweated throughout the hour, and I was emotionally stirred at the end. If anything will turn me into a believer, this would be the catalyst. If you relate to awakening and have not tried meditation yet, then I (more than!) highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until a few months later (in 2017) when I seriously tapped into my awakening – the burning urge inside me ate at me once again, and I started to slowly develop as I was now paying attention. This was when I truly realized that I could pick up on the thoughts and feelings of people upon entering the room. I hooked up for sessions with the Intuitive Life Coach, and after needing to quit the job I had, buckled down on studying and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few different books on chakras, spirituality, self-care, reiki and crystals were the vast line of knowledge I took in, and continuously study. Discovering I am an INFJ (MBTI Personality Type) and reading about others online was reassuring on the eternal struggle on the inside of being that person (I theorize that the type isn’t a big coincidence). I can assure anyone that can relate, or is experiencing a spiritual awakening, that sometimes research can help to open that door.  I found that alongside this “study period” I had an urge to clean up my life – change to a cleaner lifestyle, journal my last thoughts to my past &amp;amp; “demons”, and reinvent the relationships that were the most important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s any point I’m trying to make about my experience so far is that I’ve come to realize there’s no “reason” why I came to do all these things. It truly was this ache inside that started &amp;amp; kept knocking; and I know it won’t silence until I’m doing what I should be doing. As I’ve strived for a need to be happier with my life, I decided to only take on what I’m willing to do, and am working towards starting a business using this gift. Once I started working and focusing on myself, the pieces all just started to fall into place over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still a process though. As of the end of 2017: I just pay attention, I cut to the point but also make my decisions wisely, I speak the truth (no matter how blunt, sometimes), and more importantly – I trust my feelings/intuition. After re-evaluating my past, I saw where I had conflicted thoughts or alarm bells going off in my head but instead trusted the words that were being spoken; I swore to myself that I wouldn’t take on these burdens anymore. Even with my experience and attained knowledge that I want to pass on, I know that this is still a journey and that more can also be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of archived thoughts and article ideas (with an urge to write!), I’m finally ready to share them with the world. One of the struggles I had was how lonely this discovery &amp;amp; it’s process made me feel, and I wished there was a resource or network to turn to. I’m starting a blog with the hope that it will be meaningful to someone out there, and hope to connect with others in some way. Not all experiences are the same, but you may have found some way to relate; if you do, know that you are not alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to share my experiences and pass along tips for those alike in weekly blog posts. I hope you find my articles interesting, even if you don’t find them useful for yourself. I plan to cover aspects of everyday life and insight for those close to you, as well as pass along my newfound knowledge and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>