<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Empath Confessions</title><description>A candid look at what it's like to be an empath, clairsentient, claircognizant, and an INFJ - sharing my experiences and tips</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Empath Confessions</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.19</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 19:39:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Co-Piloting an Empath - Comfort</title><description>On a personal level, I also feel like we’re looking for the validation from an outside perspective that what we’ve concluded is not unjustified; hence, we also trust your judgment.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/co-piloting-an-empath/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a5e5d5c5e01130b9844e262</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 20:27:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/blog3-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/blog3-1.jpg" alt="Co-Piloting an Empath - Comfort"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a HSP (highly sensitive person), I haven't always been the most stable person to live with, emotionally speaking. Despite knowing that this quality is one that my husband adores about me, I have also seen first-hand how challenging it can be to deal with. Whether it’s my occasional explosion when I become overwhelmed/stressed, or simply my inability to let certain things go (I never forget anything of significance!), it’s a quirk that comes with my personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until I discovered what I am that I was able to get this under control. The responsibility of control ultimately has to be put on the empath themselves – discovering if this is who you are, recognizing its effects, and learning how to control &amp;amp; deal with it. With that being said though, it’s never going to be “scotch-free”... because as an empath, we are conduits for other people’s emotions (energy)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this series of articles as my own awakening in my abilities sparked a lot of conversations with my husband. As someone that went through her discovery alone, I wanted to share my thoughts and experiences in the hope that it would bring comfort, understanding, or even help, to anyone that ends up reading. Some topics were in order, with one of the most important being on the subject of “comfort”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even controlled, an empath will occasionally need to verbally vent to release the pent-up emotions they’ve experienced. Hopefully, every empath will at one point have someone understanding that they can occasionally confide in – which helps to serve this purpose. But there are some days that we just only see fit to release it in the comfort of our own home; and more than likely, simply will just only be comfortable to do in the presence of our significant other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are the significant other, know this: If we’re doing this in your company, THIS IS A GOOD THING! If we come home to you but start to unravel and have a need to vent about every negative thought/person/experience from the day/week, just know that we’re able to do so because &lt;strong&gt;we trust you with every fibre of our being&lt;/strong&gt;. This is also not a task that is easily done, so know that it’s literally just something we need to do from time to time to feel better. On a personal level, I also feel like we’re looking for the validation from an outside perspective that what we’ve concluded is not unjustified; hence, &lt;strong&gt;we also trust your judgment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had this conversation with my husband, admittedly it became more of a “what am I supposed to do?” on his part. I was surprised to hear that he felt useless being the listener during these rants – he expressed sincere regret in his inability to be of any help for what troubled me. This saddened me and made me make a statement that brings me to the ultimate point here: “I don’t need you to have the answers or advice, I just want you to listen”. I just want someone that I trust to listen to what I’m feeling and why, and just tell me if I’m ever out of line. After all, I'm just trying to purge the thoughts and emotions that I've picked up on that I can't speak on or do anything about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that is the message I have to pass along to significant others: we don’t need you to have the right advice to our situations, we just appreciate you being there and listening! As long as you care enough to do that, that is enough. And please, for your own sake, don’t take on any of our struggle either – it’s hard enough for us to deal with as it is; and we definitely don’t wish it to be brought upon you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that find that this isn’t the case, give yourself a pat on the back! It’s hard not to resort to this activity at certain times in life. Perhaps you have already found a more effective outlet, which is fantastic. Just remember that sometimes it is okay to verbalize buried emotions! We are still human after all, and we know that it feels better to say what we really want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an empath, the best way to avoid getting to this boiling point is being able to remove yourself from these burdens altogether. I plan to write an article on this, but will say that there are many ways to do so including being honest and forward in your decisions &amp;amp; interactions, letting go of situations that are not your responsibility, etheric cord cleansing, and carrying crystals. If you’re new to some of this, don’t be intimidated, as it will just become a part of your everyday once you start adopting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last piece of advice I gave for situations where I am truly upset and there is nothing anyone can say or do about it: just give me a hug! For empaths, a hug is the most comforting gesture anyone can offer... and I'd be surprised to meet someone who would argue with this much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While this article talks about needing to verbally vent, I am not suggesting that this be a (regular) practice. Wherein a relationship where it's mutually agreed and understood that it's a conversation with the intention to &amp;quot;sound off&amp;quot;, then it can be helpful and sometimes productive - personally, this helped me to process a lot of things during my own awakening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With that being said, I can report that now that I feel I have the thoughts and emotions in my control I have found these events to be very rare. If you're working towards this, then rest-assured that you're able to achieve your own peace in how you react to everything you receive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - The Rundown</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having done a lot of research to support my own discovery, I was saddened I couldn’t find a complete resource online. What I only found through reading one-off articles and blog posts was what it’s really like to be an empath – this is the comforting reassurance you’re&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-the-rundown/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a556e075e01130b9844e246</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/Rattlesnake---lanscape--edge--2.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/Rattlesnake---lanscape--edge--2.JPG" alt="Empath 101 - The Rundown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having done a lot of research to support my own discovery, I was saddened I couldn’t find a complete resource online. What I only found through reading one-off articles and blog posts was what it’s really like to be an empath – this is the comforting reassurance you’re not alone, and the key identifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using this to identify yourself, note that I am both clairsentient/empath and claircognizant. I do feel that I know what is attributed to each, but admit there are times when those lines are blurred for me. For a while I thought they were one and the same, but research and reflection has shown me my “double whammy” (as I jokingly call it, because it allows me to feel, know and predict what’s happening).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, know that it’s something that’s always been a part of you. Some people take a long time to learn about it, and I believe there are a lot more people out there that just simply don’t realize it (or maybe don’t want to). Secondly, it’s not just about having empathy. While by definition it can sound the same, it is by far a more in-depth experience. Many people have empathy, and we adore those that do, but that does not automatically mean they are an “empath”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be forward with the rough stuff. Because let’s be honest: if you’re an empath, you know you’ve had your days where you’ve called this a curse. The effects are harder when you’re unaware of it, but it’s easy to see what was wrong when you do come to understand it. It may not be true for all, but as some of us tend to be old souls, we sometimes find we get the tougher end of the stick in life (arguably for the sake of experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rough stuff has to do with what you endure as an empath. Before discovering who I was, this resulted in me dealing with a lot of health issues. Relatable or not, the indicator is always in what you experience when you’re around people. For example, my stomach would turn and cramp with pain when I was in a stress-filled environment or conversation. Personal conversations always resulted in me becoming a shoulder to cry on, but left me feeling drained, heavy, and responsible for helping that person.  Uneasy conversations are equally emotional too – leaving you feeling physically uncertain, enraged, cheated, and sometimes, knowing when something or someone is not right. The easiest for me to see and experience is being near someone that’s upset or angry – for me those are more like feeling a dark (sometimes leeching) cloud or a ticking time bomb in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just a few brief ways to describe how it feels, but essentially you know you’re an empath when you know this: you can feel (and I mean &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; feel) other’s emotions. If you’ve ever noticed your mood tends to change with your surroundings, and you know you’re not always “100% you”, then you know why that is. You may have had emotional explosions you can’t explain (you may find you have stressed over issues that aren’t your own; but ultimately involved you), and find you tend to be the “go-to” for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another commonality I realized through conversing with other empaths is that we have a low tolerance for media. Some people (myself included) love movies and TV shows, but have drawn a line. For example: News, in any format, is off limits in my home as I find it stressful to deal with. We can take in news and certain subjects, but know what causes an emotional and mental stir in us. For me, the local evening news just upsets &amp;amp; enrages me, but also makes me want to run out and fix everything that’s wrong. As an empath, upsetting news of any kind has the ability to ruin my mood and the rest of my day, purely based on my lack of being able to change the negative circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could probably go on with many more examples and explanations, but this should be enough to identify with. If you can relate to the experiences above, then you may very well be (or know that you already are) an empath. If I had to give it a nutshell explanation, it would be this: the ability to feel the emotions of others nearby, with the ability to experience other persons’ perspectives when you do converse. Naturally, we’re also good counsellors because the above point allows us to know what to say and how to comfort people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the unease in what we endure, there are some magical moments throughout. There is nothing that feels greater than to be in the presence of someone like-minded, or to spend time with someone that feels trustworthy. And once you understand it, it becomes easier to interpret your experiences, which should help alleviate the physical effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to publish more “how to” articles for empaths, but I encourage you to do your own research if you’re looking for identification. With luck, it won’t take you long to get the affirmation you need. I would also recommend meeting someone alike if you can, as this was what gave me answers initially. Just know that as long as you keep an open mind, and pay attention to the signs, you’ll be on the right path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Note: there are sources that say Clairsentience and Empath are one and the same, and sources that define a difference. I encourage you to look at all resources to decide. While I myself have noted differences between the two, I also identify with both and agree that the two are linked (even if the ability of clairsentience lays dormant). *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>My Discovery</title><description>There was one distinct day where I remember my life started to change. It was as if I woke up one morning and literally thought: “That’s it, things need to change”. What saddened me though was that I had already wasted too much time on the wrong things...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/my-discovery/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4e8fde5e01130b9844e233</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/bloggy.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/01/bloggy.jpg" alt="My Discovery"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was one distinct day where I remember my life started to change. It was as if I woke up one morning and literally thought: “That’s it, things need to change”. What saddened me though was that I was 27 years old, and started to feel like I had already wasted too much time on the wrong things. I simply wasn’t happy (feeling like a robot going through the daily motions), and I knew life could be better, somehow. Whether it was working jobs I felt undervalued in, or keeping to people that took advantage of my kindness, I was ready to put an end to that me. Despite recognizing there’s always still time to put oneself on a different path, I felt like kicking myself for taking so long to open my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always known I was a sensitive person, but it had always been attributed to suffering from depression and anxiety. Having experienced a lot of trauma &amp;amp; stress before I became an adult, I always assumed this was just my luck of the draw that is life. When I realized I wanted the change, I sought out counselling; I got the clarity and validation I needed on my newfound revelations. It was only now that I started to see things for what they were, and I started to deal with people by being honest, putting myself first, and letting go where appropriate. I won’t lie about it: a lot of people found their way out of my life since my transformation began, due to these motions. And I’m sure that anyone that’s experienced will agree: you sometimes have to get rid of the energies that don’t serve you any good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t much at first, but it was simply a lifestyle change in that regard: getting rid of things that don’t bring me happiness. I had time off from quitting my job and used it to focus on myself – simply taking care of myself, self-help reading, spending time on art, and one big goal that I’d struggled to achieve: lose weight. Dealing with depression/anxiety did cause a bad habit of stress eating for me. I wasn’t huge, but I definitely did not care what I ate and how much I ate. When I got married, I shed my goal weight of 10 lbs. for the dress – but that still put me on the scale for close to 170 lbs.. I had never been able to diet and exercise myself under 150 lbs. (my plateau), so I had always given up. But this time I was determined to persevere and over the course of a year, got myself down to 120 lbs.!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a feat for me. Not only did I do what I thought I couldn’t, it made me feel amazing in so many ways. I think overcoming this obstacle following my “change of heart” gave me the confidence needed to discover my true self. When I was about to turn 30, I looked up and met with an Intuitive Life Coach. Her experience with Angel Readings and Akashic Records piqued an interest in me. Of all things to bring as a question, I (even as a skeptic) wanted to know what I was &lt;strong&gt;meant&lt;/strong&gt; to do with my life. I had recently met with Career Counsellors and taken endless profiling quizzes, but it always pointed me towards the same work I had already done or titles of little interest. I, somewhere deep inside, just knew I was meant to do something specific – what I felt was “my life’s purpose”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I went about the appointment like my usual counselling sessions... but then I started getting some messages that brought more questions: I am a really old soul, I am an empath and claircognizant, and I am meant to help people. At this point in my life, helping people has always been a natural impulse to me, sadly taking over even when I don’t want to. This has been a double-edged sword up until this point as I realized I had already sacrificed a lot for people that I shouldn’t have. Truth is, I want to help, but only those that want to be helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the only thing that rang true in the moment. The rest, although eerily comforting to hear, was some spiritual talk that I didn’t know if I believed. I sat on it, and even consulted another psychic – only to receive the same messages. I started doing research on everything mentioned to me in my consultations. Before long, I realized it explained &lt;strong&gt;a lot of things&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve experienced throughout my life. All my years of depression and anxiety (in some part anyways) was suddenly explained by my ability to pick up others’ thoughts &amp;amp; emotions. Sometimes I never knew why I felt so sick to my stomach so often, and now see it happens when exposed to a stressful situation/person. My ability to predict outcomes and behaviours was also explained; sadly, as much as this has helped my managerial skills, it also serves as a shadow in certain situations. Things ever so slowly made sense after this point, and a couple months later I had my first experience with meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first real try at meditating was attending a guided group meditation led by the same Intuitive Life Coach. I honestly did not know what to expect, but went in with an open mind. My experience ended up being nothing short of indescribable! Not only did I encounter a bird that has since shown up in my dreams and in the physical world, but I also experienced myself in a setting from another perspective. My palms and my third eye felt on fire and sweated throughout the hour, and I was emotionally stirred at the end. If anything will turn me into a believer, this would be the catalyst. If you relate to awakening and have not tried meditation yet, then I (more than!) highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until a few months later (in 2017) when I seriously tapped into my awakening – the burning urge inside me ate at me once again, and I started to slowly develop as I was now paying attention. This was when I truly realized that I could pick up on the thoughts and feelings of people upon entering the room. I hooked up for sessions with the Intuitive Life Coach, and after needing to quit the job I had, buckled down on studying and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few different books on chakras, spirituality, self-care, reiki and crystals were the vast line of knowledge I took in, and continuously study. Discovering I am an INFJ (MBTI Personality Type) and reading about others online was reassuring on the eternal struggle on the inside of being that person (I theorize that the type isn’t a big coincidence). I can assure anyone that can relate, or is experiencing a spiritual awakening, that sometimes research can help to open that door.  I found that alongside this “study period” I had an urge to clean up my life – change to a cleaner lifestyle, journal my last thoughts to my past &amp;amp; “demons”, and reinvent the relationships that were the most important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s any point I’m trying to make about my experience so far is that I’ve come to realize there’s no “reason” why I came to do all these things. It truly was this ache inside that started &amp;amp; kept knocking; and I know it won’t silence until I’m doing what I should be doing. As I’ve strived for a need to be happier with my life, I decided to only take on what I’m willing to do, and am working towards starting a business using this gift. Once I started working and focusing on myself, the pieces all just started to fall into place over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still a process though. As of the end of 2017: I just pay attention, I cut to the point but also make my decisions wisely, I speak the truth (no matter how blunt, sometimes), and more importantly – I trust my feelings/intuition. After re-evaluating my past, I saw where I had conflicted thoughts or alarm bells going off in my head but instead trusted the words that were being spoken; I swore to myself that I wouldn’t take on these burdens anymore. Even with my experience and attained knowledge that I want to pass on, I know that this is still a journey and that more can also be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months of archived thoughts and article ideas (with an urge to write!), I’m finally ready to share them with the world. One of the struggles I had was how lonely this discovery &amp;amp; it’s process made me feel, and I wished there was a resource or network to turn to. I’m starting a blog with the hope that it will be meaningful to someone out there, and hope to connect with others in some way. Not all experiences are the same, but you may have found some way to relate; if you do, know that you are not alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to share my experiences and pass along tips for those alike in weekly blog posts. I hope you find my articles interesting, even if you don’t find them useful for yourself. I plan to cover aspects of everyday life and insight for those close to you, as well as pass along my newfound knowledge and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>