<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Empath Confessions</title><description>A candid look at what it's like to be an Intuitive Empath - sharing my experiences and tips</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Empath Confessions</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.19</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 02:33:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The Comeback</title><description>There's no big secret to how one bounces back from trauma, and it's not something that happens quickly or easily. For me, it took being counselled by someone who then recommended a book that opened my eyes to abuse.. and this started my cycle of recovery.  </description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-comeback/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bbd575bc46eba424c32e790</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's no big secret to how one bounces back from trauma, and it's not something that happens quickly or easily. For me, it took being counselled by someone who then recommended a book that opened my eyes to abuse.. and &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; started my cycle of recovery.  Removing the layers that clouded my heart and mind finally helped me to see the real me. Finally being in this state, I found myself on the spiritual path by immediately seeking those that could tell me who I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; am. Summing it all up now makes it sound somewhat simple, but I remind myself the process was years long and a very heart-wrenching road to take. Not that I want to focus on the negative - we all know there's been far too much of that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't want to circle back to the subject, but &lt;em&gt;the universe proves small in many ways&lt;/em&gt;, once again. Over the last few weeks, I finally gave in to an instinct I had to reach out to someone from my past. We didn't have a bad relationship; in fact, we hardly had one, which made it all-the-more awkward when we had tried. Reconnecting proved worthy though as we came to realize we &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; were in a brainwashed state of denial during those years, and we've now bonded over the atrocities of our pasts. But in the end, there was an unsettling mood that followed as we collectively dissected a lot of lies; sadly, also explaining a lot of &amp;quot;stories&amp;quot; that left me confused when I was younger. The maddening part, I must say: is learning far from the only one who's made the same accusations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it takes outside factors to put things into perspective for ourselves. While it was agreed to have been the only safe method out, the &amp;quot;walk away&amp;quot; tactic left people like us angry - wanting some form of justice for anything that had been done to us, and upset that we haven't had a hand of concern to help us. Speculation  is high that people like us become the &lt;em&gt;person who bends over for everyone but themselves&lt;/em&gt; because subconsciously: we're trying to right those wrongs. We feel broken over every act of indecency, to any specie of the planet, because we know how destructive and damaging that behaviour is; not only in it's effect to the victim, but in the sad truth about the suspect themselves. It's painful for someone like me to even listen to stories with negative circumstances and outcomes, because I sincerely feel the imbalance in creates... it's a dark and disheartening feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing on positivity was just one of the many lessons I learned along the way. Having dealt with the mental issues that came with my past, on top of other circumstances, made it so that I didn't know &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; to be positive. It was hard to learn, and even harder to accept.. at least until being ready to move on as a new person. Essentially, it had a lot more to do with accepting myself as a person &amp;amp; priority than it did anything else. Once I put myself as the goal and set my wants &amp;amp; needs as priorities, positivity found it's way. There's rough moments still, especially when on a bumpy road, but keeping your eye on &lt;strong&gt;your own&lt;/strong&gt; prize seems to allow the pieces to fall into place. Perhaps this may not apply to everyone, but for someone like myself; I found that all too often, it was easier to be negative because I was usually forcing myself to do things (which was essentially abusing my energy too) - either for other people as a &amp;quot;favour&amp;quot;, or a decision that others suggested would be good for me. Peeling away &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; person, and becoming the real me, also allowed a good amount of the negative thoughts to go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since everything has transpired, I have had a hard time dealing with the &amp;quot;what now?&amp;quot; of my past. Teetering on the idea of pressing the harshest charge seems righteous, but also alerts me to the limitless backlash; the inevitable questions on the truth of it due to the timing, etc. etc. Even with the thought of having additional victims come forward and being more of an impact, I fully expect a returned response accusing us of collaborating lies. Even without knowing the &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of people they are, I somehow don't doubt that readers could also agree with the harsh struggle of &amp;quot;how can I be &lt;strong&gt;believed&lt;/strong&gt; as a victim of closed-door abuse?&amp;quot;. Dirty hands always deny and will throw back accusations in response, which makes it the &amp;quot;he said, she said&amp;quot; that's torturous to debate. This paragraph alone gives me enough anxiety to need a day in, so you can maybe imagine how stressful it is to just consider moving forward with it. It's almost easier to leave it and let the dirt speak for itself; I'm hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, even with carrying on in my hidden state, I need to continue in such a way that allows this to &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; dictate my life. One of the many things I gave thanks for recently was the ability to have started a life that's &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different from what could've been... and is one that I want. Even though I've been in hiding on social media, I now freely share the highlights of life - trips, gifts, events, and special shots worthy of sharing; highlights that were non-existent or non-celebratory in that life. Being happy and in a position to &lt;em&gt;enjoy the finer things in life&lt;/em&gt; as I do is a result that likely fuels the anger of my abusers, and probably cites further gossip about me, but seemingly feels to be a suitable &amp;quot;retaliation&amp;quot; on my part. Not only are they not a part of the better life I lead, but it's the fact that I have gone off on my own and have done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about all of this made me realize something small, but also crucial - pressing charges is only one component when it comes to living your life after any form of abuse. While my righteous self wants the legal justice, I wonder what difference that will &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; make for me. Being mentally healthy enough, and able, to safely get out of the situation/relationship is a big &amp;amp; brave starting move, as is the healing work to distinguish the damage and it's effects. It can take any amount of time to deal with, and recover from the dissection of it, but you need to take that time. My words of advice are to not rush, or even feel rushed. Above all else though, be patient with yourself when you start to become mindful and allow yourself to be priority #1; it will still sting to say it the first few times, but you will appreciate doing it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession - Life Lessons</title><description>I remember sitting in someone's office, while being counselled on my traumatic history, and asking "why did all this happen to me?". Truth be told: no matter how much better off and different I am now, the aftermath still sees that I continue to live a sheltered life in some ways.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/confession-life-lessons/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b5a6a90c46eba424c32e745</guid><category>My Journey</category><category>Empath</category><category>INFJ</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 22:50:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remember sitting in someone's office, while being counseled on my traumatic history, and asking &amp;quot;why did all this happen to me?&amp;quot;. Truth be told: no matter how much better off and different I am now, the aftermath still sees that I continue to live a sheltered life in some ways. There are certain things that are normal for most people, and a far-fetched dream for me; while this was unfair for it's own reasons, it's only driven me to live by a better example. In addition to this, it has provided me with a wider understanding of people... even though the cruelty haunts my heart. No matter how much good I do and feel for myself, witnessing one small negative act (example: someone rudely commenting to the other when accidentally bumping into each other) hurts my very soul. Whether I like it or not, enduring traumatic events may have played a part in shaping who I am as it allowed me to learn suffering at a young age. And whether I like it or not, my familiarity with such emotions has allowed me to identify when people are feeling them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to my question wasn't as comforting as I had hoped, but then again what response would be? There is no positive aside from knowing that it made me a much stronger person to survive it and carry on. I'm sure that no matter how much better I get, there will always be those few things that can remind me of my bad experiences. While it may not be helpful to be recovering from all this while awakening as an empath, it has certainly made my life experiences a lot more interesting. When you think the world can't get any smaller, something is always waiting around the corner to remind you that it is. While I've also found my circle has grown smaller in recent years, I'm finding that I come to see the chaos I missed by not being involved. It is never obvious at the time; there's always a storm before it's clear enough to see how great (the truth) things are. The harder part of the lesson is realizing that you need to go through all the hardships to learn what you need to about life - &lt;em&gt;a prime rule I keep in mind when revealing truths to others; sometimes, they &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to experience something tough in order to build character and/or move on (from their current situation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example that I feel I sometimes preach (in lessons) is one that involves the heartbreak of losing relationships. I'm not referring specifically to romantic relationships, but any that I expected to be long-lasting and unconditional. For people like myself, it takes a road of betrayals/lies, and months of silently enduring the unease caused by that person's energy, before we are pushed to a point of &lt;strong&gt;doing something about it&lt;/strong&gt;. For me, it takes several incidents (of walking away from a conversation feeling that certain words didn't sit right, and accompanied by uneasy energy) to fill the jar that ends up being spilled when I find myself overwhelmed in the &lt;em&gt;final incident&lt;/em&gt;. The final incident sometimes isn't even as dramatic as one would expect - I find those situations don't have as much of a lead-up that affects me - but instead tend to be the final conversation in which a bluff is finally called, and (when asked to explain; because I'm &amp;quot;being crazy&amp;quot;) I let the floodgate open... It may be loud, and it may come across angry because of my energy, but the content is merely a regurgitation of the contradictions I noticed in the weeks/months prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this &amp;quot;outburst&amp;quot; ends up putting the other person in their spot, I have found this can end up being &lt;em&gt;the last straw&lt;/em&gt; for that relationship. Depending on the person, of course.. but this has unexpectedly turned into my own test of &amp;quot;Are you authentic?&amp;quot;, as I've found the end result can only go one of two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person emotionally breaks down and admits their wrong-doings, why they had lied, and we discuss how to fix the problem and our relationship; or,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The person acts as if I have ruthlessly attacked them and plays the victim - making excuses (further discussions only result in me pointing out how they are stumbling and further confirming highlighted contradictions &amp;amp; suspicions) and trying to turn the conversation by attempting to point out a flaw of mine; usually, they try to get out of the conversation by calling me crazy... all while showing themselves the door.&lt;br&gt;
When the conversation ends with the 2nd result, the relationship is usually pretty much over. I may have contact with the person depending on their needs from me, but there's usually a slim chance there's any - except in the rare instance that they come back and admit their troubles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These situations are the hardest to deal with, because we are connected to it on so many different levels. On one hand, it essentially effects the relationship and our own feelings. On the other hand, we're torn apart on the inside as a result of everything experienced. All along, we had a gut-wrenching feeling not to trust... but we give the benefit of the doubt as we're usually trying to help. Having some faith that someone close won't lie to you is also a hard fact to let go of; because we know that when we confirm that for ourselves, the trust (and sometimes respect) is completely gone. It's extremely hard to earn that back from us too, which I think is the reason why we try to look away until the breaking point. This can be damaging on it's own, and we are sometimes torn due to our invisible obligation to aid the other; we feel badly for pointing things out, no matter how truthful, and we sympathize for the other person's situation if we take away the help we were giving. I have had to teach myself to let this go, as it is what it is... but also to use the experience as a reminder to trust my initial instincts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never did get an actual answer to the question I had asked. There never is a reason or excuse for anyone to be treated badly in any way.. a simple fact that I feel is hardly mutual anymore. I've seen the pattern of people only wanting to cause pain because they have been intentionally hurt and did not heal from it. I can also confirm for a fact that it is an endless cycle if one does not get help for any of their troubles - they don't heal (meaning they aren't at peace, and likely aren't their true selves), continue to carry on with the behaviours from &amp;quot;knowing&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; lifestyle was normal&lt;/em&gt;; and it repeats with each generation raised on that normalcy. As much as I want to help everyone, I've felt like I learned the hard way that you &lt;strong&gt;sometimes need to walk away&lt;/strong&gt; from certain people. This is essential to preserving our own feelings and energy, and prevents us from the unease and heartbreak ahead. If anything at all, being who I am now and being able to read into what I can, is justifiably the real positive to &amp;quot;why me?&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Courage</title><description>Truth be told, I've been very hesitant on what to post since my big reveal was made public. I do not regret doing it, and hope that it positively effects at least one person out there.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/courage/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7f6776c46eba424c32e75b</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 01:51:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I've been very hesitant on what to post since my &lt;em&gt;big reveal&lt;/em&gt; was made public. I do not regret doing it, and hope that it positively effects at least one person out there. I do not intend to continue writing on the topic either, but I've instead found myself rescheduling a post to provide a form of update. Much like how the universe continues to prove itself smaller every day, some developments in the last couple weeks have caused me to start changing my mind. As I did not divulge enough information to indicate who my abuser was, or the relationship of that (and associated) person(s) was to me, I can say that there's &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of context missing that explains why I've had to go into hiding. Needless to say, I've still wondered if there's a way to &amp;quot;end&amp;quot; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like a cheesy way to say it, but I want to &amp;quot;end&amp;quot; my experience in the sense that I need my own closure from it. Other experiences that I have not disclosed have made it so that I feel physically unsafe due to the possibility of further confrontation. Even though I dropped off the grid by moving and keeping to myself, I unfortunately had to experience being cornered (not once, but twice!) by my abuser in a public place; all thanks to them digging for information on the web. And yes - this was despite privatizing (or canceling) everything I used, which was very little considering my feelings about social media. Being confronted in public was a very trying experience to say the least, and so it's not something I wish to have happen again. This occurred while I was recovering from the realization of (the reality of) my past.. so I'm sure it fueled my PTSD even more. In fact, I can honestly say that I would have no problem moving across country if given the option; I know I would feel safer being further away from where it happened and where associated people reside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I sometimes wonder if I had handled it the appropriate way, I easily shoot that down knowing that it's what I want regardless. When I realized that my &amp;quot;dropping off the grid&amp;quot; was the only way I could finally start &lt;strong&gt;being, and living for, myself&lt;/strong&gt;, I wanted not to be reminded by anything. It's bad enough that the memories are engraved in my mind, waiting to be triggered by an unforeseen conversation and/or action... I don't want, nor need, to put myself in any other situations that can replay a nightmare. Being an intuitive empath and working with a larger team has provided a lot more silent triggers than I even realized have occurred - I sometimes find myself stuck in a state of &amp;quot;fight or flight&amp;quot; due to the mood and/or who I am around. As this has provided a lot of frustration, and requires more down time so I can recover, it always gives me a lot to think about (and with).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, while possibly even more noteworthy, recent events of those currently close to me have made the memories replay. The decision about the outcome is still unknown, but it's made me consider what's involved in pressing charges. I've come to learn that I anticipated how emotional the process would be - and the possible confrontation involved. Even considering how stressful it would be, I think I've started to warm up to the idea; at least for the sake of officially reporting it. It will take a lot of courage should I decide to do so myself; as I've come to learn how much is needed when deciding the final outcome of the abuser. As much as I would not regret pulling this trigger (as I have every reason to), it's a heavy and life-changing decision to be made; with repercussions that will expand to other relationships, as is the case with these situations. In complete honesty: I find myself egging for the charges to be pressed, even though sympathetic to the struggle on deciding the outcome (afraid of what it will cause).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having considered how much courage has been needed to get to where I'm at now, I do have to wonder if I've been a bit harsh on myself. Anyone that can relate may agree - there have been countless days where I forced myself out of bed against my own will. The same feeling has been shared by tasks such as working, socializing, and minor life decisions (mostly when it comes to past relationships); I tend to force myself to attend with a smile painted on... meanwhile, I'm usually screaming on the inside. This seems to happen more often than not when it finally gets to a point of me not aligning with &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; anymore: the job no longer suits my needs and interests, someone's true colours show or something unforgiving is done, and the noteworthy realization when someone or group has been taking advantage of my kindness and/or skills. Truthfully, it takes a lot of courage for me to &lt;strong&gt;finally put my foot down&lt;/strong&gt;, even when I've been wanting to for a long time... I find I need some time to confirm my suspicions or see what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; happens, and I find I can't outwardly do/say what I want until I am essentially pushed over that edge - I bottle everything through every smile and let the rage pour out (verbally) when that floodgate gets opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can seem out of character, but it's not. I know I don't necessarily enjoy being that way as I actually feel terrible about it afterwards; regardless of how honest I was about myself and the truth in hiding, and on deciding whatever it was that needed to be done. A job is actually an easy example in my opinion: I feel somewhat unprofessional being someone that hasn't stuck with one company for more than 2 years, but also know that I've had my reasons for everything. At the end of the day (typically after months of debate and grinning through my frustrations), I have made the decision to move on because it was for my own good. Sometimes it's happened simply due to circumstances (which turn into a blessing), but a lot of times I find myself giving up when I'm constantly hitting a wall due to mismanagement. It takes a long time for me to give my notice, and it's never easy despite me wanting it; part of me feels guilty for &amp;quot;giving up&amp;quot;, even though I'm then past that point. Long story short though, I realize I've had to muster up a lot of courage for myself in the past... something I haven't given myself proper credit for. I do feel that's a result of having the life experiences that I've had: it's very hard to recognize the strengths through the struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing this much has made me evaluate my stance on pressing charges, among other things in my life. If I've had the courage to make it through as much as I have, I know I can do anything else I want/need. It's sometimes a hard lesson to learn yourself, and easier said than done (at least for some situations), but I find it an essential attitude towards life in general. If we weren't living life the way we wanted to, then we're inadvertently hindering (or hurting) our own happiness. Knowing this to be true is why it feels like I make drastic changes in my life.. yet they are necessary ones that leave me happier and with more peace. If you're  debating making any decisions or changes, my advice is to stop and remember what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters and remind yourself of what can be missed by not trying. We all have the courage if we look upward and try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession: Me Too</title><description>I never would've imagined I would say I am a victim of sexual abuse; let alone speak out about it in any way... So this is a very bold move for me even in the comfort of anonymity. Although it all happened over 15 years ago, the memories still surface like it happened yesterday.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/confession-me-too/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b36b9ffc46eba424c32e722</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; would've imagined I would say I am a victim of sexual abuse; let alone speak out about it in any way... So this is a very bold move for me even in the comfort of anonymity. Although it all happened over 15 years ago, the memories still surface every once in awhile. One significant event serves as a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; detailed memory that continues to feel like it happened last year. It's hard enough to speak up about it due to the chaos that follows, but I find it even harder to move on from once coming to terms with it. My consolation has been in seeing the truth and how it doesn't have to dictate who I am anymore. And for that much, I want the truth to at least be written somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experiences happened while I was young - most of it before I was in high school. Much like how my therapist diagnosed the abuse and counseled me behind closed doors, the abuse occurred out of sight of others (but sometimes, among those that didn't care otherwise). These facts alone are exactly why I'm terrified to speak, much less point a finger and press charges... because I know it would be my word against everyone that would oppose the statement. Having been asked if I would take action on it, I froze - the anxiety of facing that 2 decades later and having to purposely revisit the experience is not something I want to do. In fact, I recall stating that &amp;quot;I don't think I can be in the same room as..&amp;quot; that person; it would be unbearable and feels threatening to just think of. If anyone wants to know why this information stays as a secret for so long, I would say it's because of the aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to facing the reality of the situation itself, I found it to be heartbreaking work to move on from it. Because I was so young when these experiences happened, it was then painted as a &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; picture for me. Not only was I not able to do anything differently about the situation, but I realize I grew up having a certain (truth: unhealthy) expectation because of it. &lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; is exactly why I never saw any of that behaviour as being abusive, and is also why I carried the guilt of feeling like I allowed myself to be molested. As this was regurgitated when I started going through my life changes in my late 20's, it was a shocking slap in the face to be told what it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; was. It also shattered my reality to think that I've spent 25+ years of my life living with an imposed and dysfunctional mentality. Just as if it suddenly came up as a repressed memory, I'm left asking: &lt;strong&gt;Who am I after all this, and why did this happen to me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, no one ever batted an eye or questioned this particular person as there didn't seem to be any reason to. The behaviour that occurred in the presence of others came out as &amp;quot;jokes&amp;quot;, but even still: no one ever stopped to protect or defend me as a child/person. I have a feeling that because of enduring this, I became that kid at school that was &amp;quot;okay&amp;quot; with being the weird girl that everyone picked on and gossiped about. It was beyond rough, but seeing it as &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot;, I felt there was no escaping any of it. So I accepted it as this is how life &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I'm sure a lot of people can remember significant events from their early years, I remember the big events in addition to the moments that disturbed my young mind. As the latter obviously burns deeper into the brain, it's recognizing my memories that made me wonder what else I may have overlooked. Knowing I may have possibly repressed revealing memories frightened me so much that I went searching for them... What I recalled scared me enough to stop there: I remembered that certain attention died down after I went through puberty, and I ended up recalling what seemed to be a final conversation involving drawing a line (now that I'm developing into a woman). I've debated seeing a hypnotist since remembering this much, but am not sure if it matters anymore - the damage is done either way. Regardless, there's one memory that my brain is able to replay as if a memorized movie..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was molested, I was stunned and powerless. At this point I would think it's obvious that my abuser was an adult; I will confirm that much. What was supposed to be me taking a nap turned into the most violating, and one of the most memorable, experiences of my life. My attempts of pushing away the hand suddenly rubbing my privates went nowhere, and I eventually accepted that I couldn't physically stop it as it persisted. Feeling there was nothing else I could do, I remember going numb and staring at the wall... waiting for it to be over. Because this was all my preteen self could do in the situation, I felt like I reciprocated and &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; felt guilty for it happening. I even remember thinking to myself (while considering my options during): &amp;quot;If I scream.. no one will believe me&amp;quot;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I honestly thought I was going to carry this secret to my grave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never thought the details were important, but they ended up being the catalyst for my revelation. In addition to the physical factor involved, I was further bothered that the event occurred in a very particular situation. There's absolutely &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; excuses for anything that happens like this though.. but I'm referring to deniable situations such as &amp;quot;I didn't realize it was you&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;i was drunk&amp;quot;. Yes, this applied to the abuser's side of this story, which was another reason it never came up. I buried this deep, reminded occasionally by my guilt from it, but generally ignored it otherwise. I honestly never thought much of this event again until a couple years before my revelations; when I ran into and caught up with someone from my childhood. In one candid conversation, this person claimed they were molested by my abuser - in the exact same situation that mine occurred. At that time, I defended my abuser in my brainwashed state... in fact, I kept my experience a secret from this person too. But the details from that story planted a seed of doubt in me that sent me to therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it had to be a freaky coincidence, but let's be honest: it makes me angry to step back and look at every detail from the outside now. Now that I'm clear of my clouded thinking and have matured as a person, I cannot see there's any excuses for anything that happened. It took me a long time to forgive myself for it happening to me, and just as long to reconcile all the relationships that were either toxic or negatively effected because of it. I never realized that my own sexuality was repressed as a result of everything I've experienced, and such have struggled to be comfortable with my own body until more recently. For the longest time I found it to be normal to feel some sense of shame with anything related to sex, and carried a negative self-image as a result of the commentary, gestures, and uninvited touches I endured. I realize now I made some bad choices as my way to &amp;quot;rebel&amp;quot; and attempt to overwrite the bad thoughts and memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I never truly felt like I owned my whole body once it was first violated... but I never realized that for what it was and why as I was still young. What makes matters worse is that now that I've come as far as I have, I can honestly say some of the heartbreaking truths about my silence in those early years: I knew (for example:) screaming and getting attention would only serve to cause a scene in which I would be called crazy, and then I would never hear the end of that accusation. Deep down, my innocent young self somehow knew that speaking up on the things that happened to me would only have made things worse. Without divulging much further than saying it's based on my experience and knowledge of the people involved, I know deep down that the only response I would've received is an excuse in denial of the real problem. Again, I just see a full circle of nothing good coming from having spoken up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;, I have been able to move on with life, appearing as if it hadn't happened to me. I won't lie in that there are still PTSD triggers left to deal with (if there's anything that triggers a memory or thought of, or someone with similar personality traits or behaviour), and life needs to stop for a minute or two to get back into the right frame of mind. While it may have changed me in a way that set me back in some aspects of life, the survival experience from it all adds to my personality in such a way that I can't converse with or relate to most people. It makes me sad when everyday interactions remind me of everything I've missed (or are behind on) due to what I've been through, but I hold hope that I'll get where I want to be in the future. Sometimes, we (as survivors) have to try to remember how amazing we are to still be around and kicking after all we've been through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>On Speaking Up</title><description>The next few articles I post are going to be as raw as they come. If you haven't read the latest update; I do have content written on being a victim of abuse that I'm going to publish. I never would've imagined I would be public with such truths, but this outlet has provided enough comfort to..</description><link>http://localhost:2368/on-speaking-up/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b456030c46eba424c32e733</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next few articles I post are going to be as raw as they come. If you haven't read the latest &lt;a href="http://empathconfessions.com/static/summer-update/"&gt;update&lt;/a&gt;; I do have content written on being a victim of abuse that I'm going to publish. I never would've imagined I would be public with such truths, but this outlet has provided enough comfort to finally do so. The truth being spoken is the main goal, but I still write with the intention of reaching out to others who've had similar experiences. It has been a long, tough road and I'm not going to lie - I think &amp;quot;breaking free&amp;quot; and facing the truth, alongside the discovery of who I am, is where the credit is due for me coming out the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My whole life, I've found myself to be someone that easily blends into the background. A lot of the time it's by choice, as I've always felt overwhelmed and anxious in a crowd. When I was younger (but also sometimes now), this has happened without me even intending it... and sometimes even despite my best efforts to be included. Having been a kid that was ridiculed (and worse) by classmates, I rarely found a will to have my own voice or place among others. To make matters worse, my world outside of school was a source of unstable emotions and thoughts. I won't lie in saying this much too: for many years, especially in my teens, my source of comfort and stability was routine visits with psychiatrists that were supplemented with various pills. Having never faced the truth of it all held me under a spell that &lt;em&gt;kept me&lt;/em&gt; from being who I am truly am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I go much further, I do have a interesting fact I don't mind sharing: despite my history with mental illness and having been on various medications, I now no longer require routine therapy or take any pills. While I do NOT dispute that medication is helpful and/or necessary for certain illnesses, I have come to realize that &amp;quot;ripping off the band-aid&amp;quot; and putting &lt;strong&gt;myself first&lt;/strong&gt; made a lot of my problems (depression) go away. There are still times when darkness can get the best of me (more so now that my concern is PTSD triggers), but I remind myself it's temporary and situational. Even though it's not something I would admit, I am glad to know that I can attribute any depression and anxiety I feel to a person and/or situation; reinforcing the fact that it's temporary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I may seem like someone that's come out the other side in a much better place, I can assure you it doesn't feel that way. My own self-development (life changes and spiritually) was only part of my progress, and simply a result of me opening my eyes for what felt like the first time. There are days where I'm questioned on things that remind me of how far behind I am as a result of how my life has gone. That alone can bring some depression for me, as it's hard &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to feel insignificant amongst my peers once these &amp;quot;differences&amp;quot; have been identified. While I do my best to put it aside, I end up feeling conflicted by the one affirmation I have - no one knows what I've been through, or who I really am. Truthfully, this only hurts because it ensures no one gets to know the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; me unless they become a close friend. Depending on the situation, I find I don't get credit for my strengths and find some people read me completely wrong (and some that trigger my PTSD while outwardly doing so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that I'm beginning to preach by saying this, but it is a truthful affirmation: &amp;quot;no one knows what I've been through&amp;quot;. This is partially why I believe it's necessary to vocalize the truth - even if just in writing. The information I'm going to be sharing are truths that have stayed behind closed doors, and currently only known to less than a handful of people. While I have felt doomed by the things that I've been through, I've come to accept it as life &amp;amp; personality shaping experience - the only fact that's considered positive, in my personal opinion. Finding positives that came from the traumatic experiences allowed me to recover and move on... even when I didn't feel ready to &amp;quot;get over it&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be sparing the details, even though I will be sharing a bit about my experience with sexual abuse. Please take note if you do not wish to read this kind of content, but also know that I don't describe anything beyond what you need to know (to understand what happened). If anything hits home for you and you would like to reach out to me to talk, I welcome you to do so as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Summer Update</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greetings friends!&lt;br&gt;
I'm happy to provide an update on what's to come in the near future for Empath Confessions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen through the social media accounts over the weekend, I've decided to change the rules of the Tarot Reading Giveaways. Head on over to the page for&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/summer-update/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b394d08c46eba424c32e72d</guid><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greetings friends!&lt;br&gt;
I'm happy to provide an update on what's to come in the near future for Empath Confessions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen through the social media accounts over the weekend, I've decided to change the rules of the Tarot Reading Giveaways. Head on over to the page for details; but if you want to skip to the fun part: I've changed from weekly winners to providing EVERYONE with a free reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to announce it, but know that there are future plans so it's not just a &amp;quot;one-time use&amp;quot; ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the circumstances behind my lack of posting, I struggled to find appropriate articles to write. I have some Confessions written that I have been reluctant to post due to the sensitive and raw content... however remember that it's &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; story that I'm sharing, so why continue to hide it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a forewarning: I have written about being a victim of abuse. This is a hurdle for me to publish and share with others, but I am doing so for many reasons. It has taken me a long time to realize that the experiences added a lot to my character in positive ways, while negatively affecting me in many ways; also contributing to my late development as an intuitive empath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also written to shed light on the isolation involved, especially as I am one that felt safer going into hiding and not pressing charges. A lot of people make quick judgments about accusations and stories that have surfaced years after the fact, and I want to share my story to explain (some reasons) &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not related to &lt;strong&gt;being&lt;/strong&gt; an empath, I want to share my recovery story for anyone else out there that's been a victim of abuse. Possibly more than anything though, it's noted that this will be the first time I share one particular secret outside closed doors. It was extremely difficult to write - so much so that I couldn't focus on the screen at times... and this is when I realized I can still do some recovery work by talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revamp of the site has been delayed due to the drastic change involved. As I intend to gear this to become more of a &amp;quot;business&amp;quot; for me, I'm well aware that the whole site needs to change. I promise this will become easier to look at as it will become simpler to navigate, and posts (one per page) will be organized by topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any feedback, feel free to contact me through the social media accounts or email me (see About Me for link)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you again soon! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession: Regret</title><description>Whatever the regret, I know that there's always a way to deal with it that depends on what it is you want from it. Whether it's doing something or going somewhere specific, making it right by someone you care about, setting and working towards an abandoned goal, or simply coming to terms and...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-confession-regret/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b033865c46eba424c32e705</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 01:36:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I've fallen off this wagon, I find myself filled with regret. I haven't felt comfortable writing about it, but there have been many thoughts on my mind lately that I've needed to vocalize. It's not so much for my own sake, but after realizing I knew I was feeling everything for a reason; others have been, or are, there too. Whether the situation itself is familiar or not, I would imagine one can find relatable scenarios. Another emotion I struggle with is regret, and mostly because it's reach can come from many sources. One thing I've found important to recognize is that most times (or perhaps almost all times!) you have absolutely no reason to feel this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I want to do an Empath 101 article on &lt;strong&gt;regret&lt;/strong&gt;, I find it difficult to present a clear consolation on it. Despite currently struggling with it, I have overcome my past regrets by realizing the &amp;quot;filter&amp;quot; in which it came from. For me personally, I had a lot of experience growing up with being guilt-tripped into doing things for others. This caused me to have a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; conditioned outlook on not only people, but expectations from people and relationships. Diving deeper into this could be a book of it's own, but I mention this as I now realize it added a lot to my life experience and shaping as an empath. And sadly, it hurts to even admit that after all the years of therapy needed for it - there's a small proof that it possibly happened for a reason. Regardless, this evaluation and healing made me realize that my thinking is to blame for my regret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripping away the regrets that lingered from my past and from having that conditioned thinking left me with realizing I can &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; not to have that emotion. Surely there are small regrets that will happen throughout life either way, but I'm referring to the one's that haunt us and regurgitate from time to time. These need not happen unless we truly are not at peace with ourselves; and this applies to everyone. Whether it's releasing a regret tied to guilt by focusing on the good that came afterwards, and/or making amends on the &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; regrets, the work can be done to wipe the slate clean. From there, following one's own path while remaining open-minded and honest has proven that it can be easy to live without regret. And if I'm ever having trouble with this thinking, I look at the situation and remember that everything happens for a reason - most times, I end up seeing the truth that makes me laugh and feel much better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had a few situations in life where I felt true regret for something I said or did. This didn't happen often because I HATE to be in any wrong, and am always trying to help the next guy even while it's hurting me... yet I've had a handful of events. When I took the time to look back on my life, I realized what happened had transpired due to my kindness having been used until I had no other choice but to explode, and harshness (be it words and/or actions) was the result. Obviously guilt was then induced due to the &amp;quot;odd&amp;quot; behaviour and regret was born, however I realize I have to question &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; I'm regretting it. Do I regret that I realized I needed to make a decision or statement that someone else didn't like, because it was something I needed to do for me? Never again! In fact, I now realize that some of my &amp;quot;outbursts&amp;quot; were the only way I was able to see, process and react to the truths I was picking up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As being able to &lt;em&gt;tap into&lt;/em&gt; other people can sometimes provide a cloud of depression accompanied by sad and/or dark (and sometimes insulting) thoughts, it's hard to ignore everything. Add in the distraction that is the rainbow of other people and it's hard to stay unphased by the emotions, especially when staying in their company. It's sometimes all one can do to stay focused on what they need to depending on the situation they're surrounded by. I have personally found this to be my daily scenario once again as I recently accepted a permanent full-time job; in a corporate head office environment. While I'm finding things are going well in that I haven't had any issues or negative feedback, I'm really overwhelmed -- by taking on the stress and responsibility, facing the &amp;quot;emotional&amp;quot; days, and the regret from my downtime. While I have no regrets with how I have spent my time, I admit I've come to question myself (once again) as I struggle to find time to properly focus on this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that while I can ignore what I pick up on, the energy attached to it and any emotions I may have processed need to be dealt with at the end of each day. While this isn't something new, I've begun to question why I place myself in such situations... leaving me with little time to be authentic and free. This has contributed a lot to my lack of updates on here, as I am not as clear-minded as I used to be when I started writing. Realizing that &amp;quot;pushing out&amp;quot; posts is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; how I want to be doing this, in addition to being short on time, has stirred a lot of questions in me; causing some regret. It's not so much regret for what's here as plans are still on schedule, but more-so for feeling as if I lost myself just as I was healing and getting familiar with &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive note - there's nowhere to go but forward unless you give up, which is not what I intend to do in this case. My way of coping with this regret is considering the possibility that (maybe!) this hiccup was meant to teach a lesson, and realizing that there's still plenty of time to get back to where I want to be. Whatever the regret, I know that there's always a way to deal with it that depends on what it is you want from it. Whether it's doing something or going somewhere specific, making it right by someone you care about, setting and working towards an abandoned goal, or simply coming to terms and feeling ready to move on for your own good - there's always a positive side to be found if you look for it. If there's any message I hope to pass on from this, it's knowing to look within and seeing regret as a lesson (decision) in which to push yourself forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Update</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that I've fallen off my schedule of publishing weekly.&lt;br&gt;
After having accepted a new full-time opportunity, I'm admittedly struggling with finding the time needed for a weekly post. In addition to this, I've been trying to figure out how best to move forward with this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/update/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ae25352c46eba424c32e6ee</guid><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 01:48:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that I've fallen off my schedule of publishing weekly.&lt;br&gt;
After having accepted a new full-time opportunity, I'm admittedly struggling with finding the time needed for a weekly post. In addition to this, I've been trying to figure out how best to move forward with this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have new plans for Empath Confessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be posting 2 articles on a monthly basis. I haven't set any particular dates yet, but will announce something very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am changing my Tarot Reading Giveaway contest to a &lt;strong&gt;WEEKLY&lt;/strong&gt; event. Remember that in order to qualify, all you have to do is Subscribe! (I won't be using the Subscribers list for any other purposes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the near future, I plan to revamp the blog into a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, feel free to keep in touch through the social media accounts and check back for more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - Forgiveness</title><description>One of the emotions that I have found myself struggle with is forgiveness. Forget the fact that I remember what people say when it's anything of significance, or that sets off an alarm bell...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-forgiveness/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5acab6c6c46eba424c32e6db</guid><category>Empath</category><category>INFJ</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 23:46:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/04/14---Empath-101-4.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/04/14---Empath-101-4.png" alt="Empath 101 - Forgiveness"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the emotions that I have found myself struggle with is forgiveness. Forget the fact that I remember what people say when it's anything of significance, or that sets off an alarm bell - just having the hunch on one's true intentions makes it hard to be forgiving when they speak and act otherwise.  Additionally, the barrage of negative messages &amp;amp; energies at times can cause me to struggle with my own self esteem &amp;amp; forgiving myself - especially when picking up on the &lt;em&gt;Negative Nancy&lt;/em&gt;'s thinking ill of me for no reason. It can be hard to deal with it all, but there's a lot to realize for coping with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting off with the tough stuff, yes - it's hard to be an Intuitive Empath in situations where you can't escape dealing with negative energies. One example of where I find this problem a lot is at work; as it's a situation where I'm stuck in the same space with many other people, and some/most that clash with my personality. Some days can be fine, but some days can be hard to get through when I feel surrounded by negativity. Having days where you feel like you're physically fighting off someone's bad mood (example: feeling the heat and tension from a co-worker that's having a bad day, while sometimes also picking up that they've thought an ill statement of me/others as a result) can cause a huge drain that requires time to recover from. Having this happen so often has led me to re-evaluate my outlook on relationships in a way, as I deemed this necessary to protect myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having so many experiences where time is spent waiting to see if someone follows through on their word or otherwise, has set a tone for how I approach people with similar energy. If I encounter someone that comes off as possibly untrustworthy (&amp;quot;shady&amp;quot;), I put up an alternate front; being nothing but basic and pleasant while guarded, which makes it hard to build a relationship without their effort for it. While I'm &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; necessarily recommending this be how to deal with these personalities, I will say that this is what works for me. Again, I personally feel as though I've learned the hard way on who to trust and help - I feel it necessary to highlight a personal disclaimer that I always have, and will continue to be, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; person that's always willing to and looking for ways to help... but certain persons may never get to see that side of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having dealt with enough to say I've learned the patterns of those that are two-faced and/or self-destructive, I've come to a point of knowing time will always tell in revealing their true nature, and play out accordingly. In rare occasions, I've seen someone prove themselves in a positive way and it ends up being their protective front or past baggage that negatively foreshadows their presence... but most of the time, I find karma eventually does the job. Whether it's an event that turns their life onto a different path, or that sparks a life lesson or decision which in turn changes them, I find there ends up being a slim chance that I ever see these people again. Having the patience to wait and see things play out usually provides reassurance that dealing with such energies was only temporary, and the change even benefiting the do-gooders such as myself afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living with such uneasiness, not to mention the interactions, or worse (when it comes to relationships that are close), can cause a lot of questions to surface about oneself. For me personally, I have a hard time forgiving myself for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being (too) nice to people that didn't deserve it,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;giving a (second) chance to those that felt untrustworthy,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having put myself into more &amp;quot;trust-testing&amp;quot; situations, even after feeling that I know better.&lt;br&gt;
While this list also applied to me before I discovered who I am, I find it still highly applicable - the only thing different is that I now know other's moods/intentions. Regardless of the time and circumstances, I find it hard to be forgiving of myself when I feel negatively influenced by things I pick up on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has taken a while to learn to forgive myself for what I see as my past mistakes, as I've learned they were simply life lessons on what and who to believe. I've also learned to be forgivingly gentle with myself as I encounter negative energies and thoughts that directly affect me. It hasn't been easy - I won't lie; sometimes it takes centering myself and remembering what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters (to me) to block out what's nagging at me. After all, it usually isn't my business to know most of what I come to know anyways; so I &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; shouldn't let it concern me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to other people, it's hard to set a standard or guideline on their trustworthiness. Sometimes people are good natured but prone to making hasty &amp;amp; risky/bad decisions, and sometimes people think &amp;amp; believe they have the best intentions when they truthfully don't - these types of personalities are the hardest ones to work with and learn from, which can easily play with your emotions. This has turned into my criteria on energies to be cautious with, hence my approach with those that give me any uncertainty. Should I feel uneasy for reasons possibly related to not being able to trust someone, than I already know it will be hard to be forgiving towards them. I feel that I owe it to myself to dodge the roller coaster by avoiding a friendly relationship with such persons in the first place; this allows me to be forgiving of myself for at least doing right in that regard, and avoiding my own hurt from possibly getting entangled in something I don't like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone will likely have their own examples to work from as they recognize what they need to, but I hope my explanations provided some relativity (or even some solace) for those looking for it. While I think it's always going to be a little hard to forgive myself, I at least take confidence from knowing I can tell who to be forgiving with. Above all else we must remember that even though we are Intuitive Empaths so that we can help others, their problems are &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; our responsibility and we must forgive ourselves when it doesn't resolve the way we see it should. At the end of the day, we too go home to our life, family and priorities, and must remind ourselves to reserve our primary energy &amp;amp; focus for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession  Patience</title><description>Patience doesnt come easy to me, and often wears thin as a result of intuition. Before knowing I had such intuition, my patience was aggravated by outside factors that pushed me away from whatever situation or decision I was in.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-confession-patience/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5abadf51c7630e2294972dc3</guid><category>Empath</category><category>INFJ</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:29:49 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/12---Confession-3.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/12---Confession-3.JPG" alt="A Confession  Patience"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patience doesnt come easy to me, and often wears thin as a result of intuition. Before knowing I had such intuition, my patience was aggravated by outside factors that pushed me away from whatever situation or decision I was in. Some people judge me negatively for being a person whos quick to move, as (in some cases) I wont stay in one place too long but would never entertain the idea of understanding &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;. Very few, myself included (although I argue with myself about this at times), realize its due to our deep morals and values that take priority. Call it, or me, what you will but at some point I see theres a good reason to all my hasty decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to everyday things, I have about as much patience as time allows me. As every minute counts for me, I schedule most of my life. Between making sure I get at least 8 hours sleep, to working my full-time job and the blog, and the little things in between all that, Ive ensured my time is valuable. I believe this is actually a crucial lesson everyone needs to learn for oneself, especially if theyre starting off in a career and/or their own business. Being someone that sees no good reason to waste time at anything (for whatever reason), my lack of patience turns into an anxiety that pushes me to do something about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, patience comes easy in certain situations. Awaiting news, following a plan, and deciding to give a chance, are among the uncertain situations wherein the anxiety can be tamed. But only to a certain degree Unfortunate as it may be, this can be a struggle in situations where were waiting on a chance or change. And when other factors (namely new messages/facts that come up) come about during this wait, patience gets tested even further and sometimes helps to come to a conclusion faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I assumed this was all due to my personal character, and from my own negative experiences. This is likely true for others that can identify with what Ive just said, but I had come to realize this is due (at least partially) to my intuition. What I had named as &lt;em&gt;outside factors&lt;/em&gt; turned out to be truth and insights I receive; causing anxiety as I endured and ignored it building up until I couldnt take it anymore. Having realized that all of my seemingly unexpected exits led me to more clarity and happiness, as well as the path I have found myself on, I carry no regrets for any of my decisions. Much like what Ive written on before  many times, everything has to happen a certain way for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing that life must sometimes play out in its mysterious way for good reasons is exactly why we must take caution with every insight, and learn to become patient. And not just patient, Ive learned  Ive also learned its sometimes more insightful to just be genuinely innocent and unknowing, and as the positive note to the negative front (in all situations). The latter approach comes with some weight at times, more so when the answer comes in flat-out ignorance or the insight of their nasty (albeit: always incorrect and is clearly about them) assumption/opinion about you. While tough to deal with times, these are the moments where being our patient self pays off; eventually, karma plays out in its own form as the repercussions of their behaviour affect their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While patience is a virtue for some, its sometimes a hard skill to control for people like myself. Thats why, admittedly, Ive had a few moments in the past where Ive (finally) become so upset that I explode and dont have control of what I say. These moments can feel good as theres baggage to unload, but obviously comes across as crazy to anyone unsuspecting of it. We regret this action immediately, as the outburst &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; isnt in our nature, but accept the consequences are likely how things should be anyway. Perhaps weve decided enough is enough and wanted to call it sooner, or perhaps we needed to have the altercation. Truthfully Ill never know the real answer as to why, but reflecting on such events only reassures me there were many valid reasons for how I acted (and reinforces the need to not dwell on anything from the past!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when things are going great enough that patience isnt a struggle, I find I still have a rocky relationship with it. Its something to be recognized, but also to be bartered with at times. It is our greatest test in life, considering our intuition, and it can also be our greatest weakness in certain situations.  How we choose to deal with that varies depending on what aids each person and situation, but nevertheless we know we need to tame it. Bottom line though: this is one of the few aspects about being me that I dont wish on anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Announcement: Starting in April, I will be pulling a monthly winner for a free Tarot Card Reading! Winners are chosen from those that Subscribe to the website (look for the Subscribe button at the top right of the page), and will be contacted through email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Co-Piloting an Empath - Understanding</title><description>Whether its a packed movie theatre, store, or even familiar environment, being surrounded by a lot of people has an intense effect on me. Picking up on current moods and troubles, and receiving thoughts on those near me, is the majority...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/co-piloting-an-empath-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ab0806cc7630e2294972db6</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/11---Co-Piloting-an-Empath-3.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/11---Co-Piloting-an-Empath-3.jpg" alt="Co-Piloting an Empath - Understanding"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether its a packed movie theatre, store, or even familiar environment, being surrounded by a lot of people has an intense effect on me. Picking up on current moods and troubles, and receiving thoughts on those near me, is the majority of my experience while trying to go about my day or enjoy myself. Depending on the setting, this can be completely unavoidable and unwelcome at times, which can throw me off my own focus (and sometimes put me in defense mode momentarily). As this is just the nature of how things can be for people like me, we find our own way to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a significant other to one that experiences this, it can sometimes be of help to understand these situations. If given the choice, I avoid crowded situations, but otherwise mentally prepare myself to focus on whatever experience I go for. More times than not, its usually routine tasks such as working and shopping that throw me through emotional roller coasters and potentially cause some anxiety  due to not being able to escape from the person/environment and not being able to directly deal with what Ive picked up. Similar to picking up on ones secrets, picking up on ones judgments (towards others, and me) sometimes sets a tone that has me careful to get out of the situation as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When going out in public, I arm myself with some crystals and mental preparation so as to take everything on confidently. But even with my development and confidence, I still find I can only take so much and need to find a retreat from a handful of certain situations. Having this happen while working can be challenging, but a lifelong lesson of mine is being able to adopt a face and mood and hang tight. Doing this in settings that dont require my presence makes me wonder why Im in that situation to begin with, and thus I dont have the will or energy to pretend and get grumpy... sometimes backing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope in describing the experiences is to help others to try and understand what its like to be in our shoes. We can manage, and were usually not complaining about who we are, but we all have our limits and our days. Some days we just need to retreat into ourselves for self-care reasons, and sometimes we just have a lower limit than usual on being exposed to outside quarrels. On our own, this allows the rare occasion to unintentionally alienate oneself depending on the retreat taken (where we feel we needed to). If we have someone with us on the other hand, it could be a different story. Understanding friends can help in the forms of distraction (change the subject or the activity), or leading (us out of) the situation; given they are equipped, and willing, to do so for us. Our significant other, where available and willing, can be a great help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether we tell you or not, the amount we pick up on when we go out with you on a simple outing can be vast  and you do catch a bit of it, if you look for it. Between observing our body language (when we tense up; when we suddenly look at someone with intent; when we look like we suddenly feel sick), and paying attention to muttered comments (Really?!, Watch, this persons gonna..), you can get an idea by watching us in busy surroundings. Should you ever discover us in a frozen, or frantic, state then you should probably be aware of what that could mean. What causes this reaction in us can vary from person to person, but generally stems from feeling unsafe. It doesnt necessarily mean something terrible is about to happen, but in some occasions, we do feel overwhelmed by the thought/person that caused it. In the rare instances that this &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; throws us off, having a supportive hand is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes recognizing the messages, and disclosing your concerns (what situations you want personal support with) to determine how you and your partner would want to go about this. Personally (as an example:), my husband offers a form of comfort in the few occasions where were stuck standing in a large crowd of people  if I ever start to feel anxious (usually when waiting and/or in a line, I noticed), hell grab my hand, ask if Im alright, and do his best to distract me with humour. Admittedly at first, it was merely a sweet gesture that sometimes got off to a rocky start, but my appreciation of his offer/concern grew into a small practice of my own  I allow myself to be calmed by the comfort, and focus on him in intent of blocking everything else out which helps! It is just an easy suggestion if I do say so myself, but youll know what best helps you in uncomfortable situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not matter what though, understanding how it all works and effects you can be really insightful for your partner. Im not just talking about in terms of understanding the effects, but in terms of how they see you as a person. Most of us hate to admit it as weve naturally put ourselves last for a good part of our lives, but because of our intuition, we carry heavy hearts. We care about the smallest issues, having being able to see what difference each effort at it makes, and care about the world as a whole, whether its the environment, equality, injustice and any problem we see as the evil against us. As draining as it is to carry these thoughts as well as our own, we still believe things can be made better. Knowing most people would give up on certain things as opposed to having that thought, we can only hope to continue to be pure person every day  a trait not common!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accompanied with what seems like odd new activities, some significant others may feel uncertain or even intimidated (if youve recently awakened). I personally found it helpful to explain the simple facts and philosophy behind my new practices, throwing in some light-heartedness by cracking jokes and using sci-fi metaphors. Even if this isn't something in belief of the other person, I've seen how it can help build a bridge over the gap of uncertainty. Making light of things, having open-book conversations, and being patient, helps create a better understanding; which can, sometimes, create a more solid relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - Truth</title><description>Even as a developed empath, you know all too well how heavy the effects can be. If youre like me and are pursuing a career helping people, then you know how important it is to understand how it works and how to keep it in your control.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-truth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa741e2c7630e2294972dac</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 02:02:13 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/10---Empath-101---3.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/10---Empath-101---3.jpg" alt="Empath 101 - Truth"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even as a developed empath, you know all too well how heavy the effects can be. If youre like me and are pursuing a career helping people, then you know how important it is to understand how it works and how to keep it in your control. Having said that, Im sure a lot of us are just trying to find a good way to put this ability to use anytime we deal with others. With that come a lot of emotions in the forms of what you pick up, and what is shared. Sometimes the harder emotions to deal with can be the secrets you keep (the dark/hurtful thoughts that instinctively seem to pop up at certain times).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im going to try my best to not reiterate some things that Ive spoken of in previous articles, but there were some points I mentioned that I feel like expanding on. In this sense, control is in the form of discretion. Recently, I wrote about being in a situation where I heard life altering news that didnt surprise me and actually explained my previous/recent thoughts and intuition on the persons involved. In the moment of receiving the news, I used my shock of oh, it &lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt; happen! to maintain my surprised response to the conversation. Even though Im disclosing some of the new details about myself to close friends, I tend to keep certain thoughts a secret unless theres a reason to bring it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me back to a point I made about how theres certain thoughts that you wouldnt dare bring up unless theres evidence (hence why I refer to them as the dark/hurtful thoughts that become secrets). Most of you easily register a few of that idea Im sure, but for those that want clarification  Im talking about the thought of someone with a secret in the form of a terrible addiction, cheating, betrayal, or information that would hold weight on someone significant to them (whether past, present, or future). Just going through that list, its easy to see why this is the information you dont necessarily want to be imagining unless its true, and sometimes you just have to wait and see what unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more reasons why you shouldnt just go ahead and share these thoughts right away, and its not limited to the possible repercussions you may face. One thing that Ive learned from observing and reflecting on certain situations is that even if and when you feel reason to bring it up, it may not be your place to do so. While we can flourish from being the person that addresses it for those seeking an answer (due to their own reasoning), its not for us to &lt;strong&gt;provide&lt;/strong&gt; the idea. Another crucial lesson Ive learned along the way (and is one reason why I think Im still learning this about the hard stuff) is that everything, even the tough, backstabbing stuff, happens for a reason. This is really why we must silently hold these thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call it cruel if you want, as I know I have given my own experiences in life. Even when I was meeting with my Intuitive Life Coach and coming to terms with my discovery, I asked why it is that Ive been put through so much. Her answer: to shape me into whom Im to be. It was very hard to argue with that considering the rare experiences Ive been through, even though I still wish a lot of that wouldve been different. But that is a truth that applies to a lot of things in life, including these secrets  people would rather be without it, but theres some crucial life lesson within it. Whether its learning not to trust people as much as you have, learning how you failed (as a partner) in a relationship, or pushing yourself to become a stronger person after hitting rock bottom, theres always a positive outcome to be found at the end of a terrible situation. And &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; experience is what shapes us as a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we were here to warn everyone about everything that would happen, people wouldnt know how to operate on his or her own. Much like the issue with technology, people can be too dependent on being told what to do and that defers one from needed experience and the process of exploring &amp;amp; deciding for oneself. As helpful as we can be to coach people in the right direction when theyre conflicted, or provide an insight on prospects, were not here to dictate any ones narrative. On the flip side, we can use the positive potentials we see to encourage one in that direction  but only if theyre receptive to it and see it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one perk about picking up on such things is the ability to aid ourselves, and those close to us (as we choose to). One lesson I learned for myself was that clearing my clutter allowed me to think and connect more clearly, which allowed me to notice what I pick up on much easier. And thats just the beginning as we can use this ability in everyday situations to figure out what to do.  One example I can share is my experience within workplaces: I pick up on the emotions of co-workers, sense the problems, and if its something about the environment or company/management that I can confirm, I know Im not going to be happy if I stay and therefore bow out peacefully. I also use emotions I pick up on to know how to react to others  this has been beneficial as a pop-up friend that offers a chance to vent, and/or a positive chat, which always leaves everyone feeling good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to go with your instinct and follow it to find out what it is youre picking up on. Speaking the truth, being true to yourself, and following the signs you receive becomes the new way of living. No matter what trials it still takes me through, and the uncertainty still ahead, I know being this way is still putting me on the right path. As I spoke necessary truths to people, I also began to notice I could finally get what I needed even if it meant finding out where not to turn. Despite the roller coaster it may sometimes cause, truth is your best friend now, and you should embrace it in every way possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>BRB!</title><description>I will be taking a break this week, but will return next Tuesday evening with an Empath 101 article!
I want to take this opportunity to thank everyone that is currently reading!
As I am not paying for any advertising, I am relying solely on word of mouth and social media to gain exposure... </description><link>http://localhost:2368/brb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9c94f6c7630e2294972da2</guid><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/9---BRB.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/03/9---BRB.png" alt="BRB!"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be taking a break (from posting an article, anyway) this week, but will return next Tuesday evening with an &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empath 101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; article!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take this opportunity to thank everyone that is currently reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; paying for any advertising, I am relying solely on word of mouth and social media to gain exposure. To block spam, I have added moderating to comments within the blog and Facebook group. The original intent is to prevent any kind of &amp;quot;garbage&amp;quot; from getting involved, and not meant to frustrate or deter any readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While (understandably, I get it!) it's awkward to follow along and engage when no one else appears to be, I would like to invite fans to get involved. I have seen a great amount of people that come across and like the blog, as well as my social media accounts and their posts, but see not nearly as many people are following. I only wish to bring this up in hopes of personally reaching out and saying: &lt;em&gt;if my blog is of interest or help to you, please feel free to connect with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow and stay connected on any of these social media accounts:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Facebook:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/empathconfessions/"&gt;www.facebook.com/empathconfessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Instagram:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/empathconfessions/"&gt;www.instagram.com/empathconfessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pinterest board:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/ashleydtilson1/empath-confessions/"&gt;www.pinterest.com/ashleyt/empath-confessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of you have taken the opportunity to reach out to me to ask if I would offer a reading. I thank you greatly for this experience, and your reactions and feedback have helped me even more than you may know (at first, I wasn't sure if I could give a reading to someone I've never met or spoken to, but - &lt;strong&gt;wow&lt;/strong&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am slowly working towards launching my website for readings and coaching, I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; currently doing this to gain experience. Anyone else that is intrigued can feel free to contact me (through whatever venue suits best - you can check my &lt;a href="http://empathconfessions.com/static/about-me/"&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt; page for my email address). My readings are purely Intuition-based, but I also use and incorporate tarot cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently maintaining this blog (and it's social media accounts) alongside my full-time job and home (family) life. While I wouldn't dare complain about the amount of work needed to do all that, I must admit I wish I had more time to dedicate to this. It is my honest hope that as my blog grows, I can gain the experience and exposure needed to turn these hobbies (writing and giving readings) into my new full-time career. Until then, I kindly ask everyone to bare with my response time (but know that I at least follow-up and make arrangements the same day), but know that I welcome all inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I welcome fans to reach out personally, or at least connect, as I would like to create a relationship. I look forward to the chance to give back to you, and plan to start offering promotions to subscribers/followers in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Confession - Overcoming Obstacles</title><description>As much as I want to share my weight loss story with those that have questions or are looking for advice, I also want to share this story for its core lesson: the ability to overcome an obstacle.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-confession-obstacles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a9604d4c7630e2294972d8f</guid><category>Empath</category><category>My Journey</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 02:20:38 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/8---Confession-2.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/8---Confession-2.png" alt="A Confession - Overcoming Obstacles"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as I want to share my weight loss story with those that have questions or are looking for advice, I also want to share this story for its core lesson: the ability to overcome an obstacle. After what seemed like rock bottom for me mentally, I looked at my life and saw that I wanted to change things - more importantly, who I am. Severing ties with that which I no longer wanted to be a part of, I came to a point of realizing that it was crucial to also make some necessary changes on myself. One big thing that stood out for me, as it is also the image of something I dont want to become, was my appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life/style saw that I was never a skinny person: I hit puberty at a young age, I had depression &amp;amp; anxiety growing up, I ate whatever I wanted to deal with stress, and I went off into the adult world with no concept of how to eat properly (or any understanding of the damage I had already been, and would continue to be, doing). While routine check-ups with the Doctor always indicated I was overweight, the word obese was never used  and it was never discussed further, so I thought nothing of my weight. But as many would agree  there comes an age when you start to realize that your metabolism is not the same as it used to be, and that you start to feel generally unhealthy when consuming too many bad foods/drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my twenties, I had my try at losing weight on many occasions. I was never athletic or involved in sports, and thanks to an old spinal injury I also dont last long with a workout schedule  which makes things difficult and more discouraging for me.  Diet plans such as low-calorie and low-carb were the easiest methods for me, but only resulted in me losing 20  25 lbs. over the course of months, and then not being able to lose more. Repeatedly being stuck at my plateau (always at 150 lbs.) threw me back into a state of depression, and I actually started to believe I was meant to be this size, and meant to be someone who struggled (with weight). Before long, I would drop the diet in an attempt to get my self-esteem back after feeling like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once went to an annual check-up and weighed in around 180 lbs.  this was my first wake-up call that I was actually bigger than I should be. Even though I had already dieted before this point, I never saw it as more than a means to shed some pounds (and not as a big and permanent change). Despite still not having an idea of what weight I should be, I knew I needed to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. Truthfully, Im still unsure if this contributed at all to my personal revelation, but it definitely gave me the understanding I finally needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without reiterating too much from &lt;a href="http://empathconfessions.com/static/my-discovery/"&gt;My Discovery&lt;/a&gt;: there was one morning when I woke up and as if I had a revelatory dream, I had decided I needed to change everything about my life. While (admittedly) some of these changes involved removing people from my life that were a bad influence, I saw it in myself to also take the steps necessary to ensure that I also never turn into that kind of person. For me, my weight easily registered as a major factor granted, that I could actually change it. Seeing this as one of my top obstacles in life, I knew it would be a lot of hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reasoning is for making your change, you should ultimately be doing it for yourself. While I looked to what it was I didnt want to be as my motivational image, I knew I was doing it so I would be happier with myself  with how I looked and felt, and how much of a difference that makes in all aspects of life. I knew this was going to be one of the hardest things I would do (as I was aiming to get under 130 lbs.), and that it would only work if I stick with it, and change my lifestyle for good. As I maintain time and time again: &lt;strong&gt;determination&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;persevere&lt;/strong&gt; is really where the credit is due in my achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often ask me what my secret is, or what pill I took. Most assume Ive been taking diet supplements and was involved in some intensive regime, but its actually much more simple than most realize. One of the first things I put out there is one of the facts that Ive learned for myself: if youre stressed out and not happy with your life, a lot of effort can make a very small difference. Sort out what you need to so that youre in the right frame of mind; I knew that stress would cause me to rush to junk/fast food (and/or overeat) and impede the motivation required, so I eliminated as many stressors as I could beforehand. In the end, changing my lifestyle was the real change made when I lost weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to finding natural remedies or solutions to issues I had needed medication for, I started to pay more attention to what I ate. I did as much research as possible, including the science behind diet plans and food. As with any obstacle, I wanted to be fully informed and prepared before I started the plan. Doing this allowed me to create my own plan, which Im happy to share for those looking for advice. Just keep in mind that no matter what happens, and even no matter what the obstacle, you have to continue to reinforce the thought to not give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My weight loss (which was a total of over 50 lbs.) took me roughly a year from beginning to end. Having said that, there is no end to the changes adapted in order to maintain this weight  having worked so hard to get to a weight I havent been at since I was a teenager, I could never allow myself to go back. Cutting out junk/fast and processed foods is just one practice Ive learned to adopt permanently, and is something that can make a big difference on its own. Using an app to budget the amount of calories I need (based on weight, etc.), and eating balanced meals* that fit within that, was the strictest Ive had to be on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I saw this whole process as more of a lifestyle change, I was able to have fun with it. I still had days along the way where I wanted to give up - namely the period when I was stuck at 150 lbs. yet again  but I reminded myself that it just takes time and &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt;. While I did do workout routines and yoga classes off and on in the beginning, my one consistent was actually the neighbourhood retreat I took every morning; I would queue up some music that made me feel good, put on my headphones, and went out for a walk. This 20-30 minute stroll isnt even the intent of exercise, but is still better than nothing (and is very rejuvenating for the soul).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cant tell you that there was anything more significant to the process than what I have already shared. I kept at it, and months later I saw the results I thought to be impossible. For months I didnt fit into any clothes and, as it made no sense to buy any while I was still losing weight, it took a year to finally get a new wardrobe. Someone whose closet used to be filled with Ls and XLs is now filled with Ss and XSs. I never thought I would see such a day (I wouldve been happy to be a M!), but its all the proof I need that I can do anything I put my mind to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While very different from my other posts, I want to share this information in hopes of inspiring anyone else like me that has struggled with the issue. I thought it to be impossible, but came to realize that is only my mind choosing to make it fail. Like everything else in life, it takes work and commitment to cement the end results you want. No matter what it is youre trying to achieve, know that it can be possible as long as youre determined and willing to follow through with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* My meals included protein shakes (with VegeGreens, and using Almond milk), and homemade meals consisting of a protein (ex: skinless chicken breast) and salad / vegetables (try to stay green), sometimes with a small serving of long grain rice. Beverages were restricted to water and green tea, while I also consumed 64 oz of cranwater (pure Cranberry and water) per day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Empath 101 - Learning Curve</title><description>In the beginning, simply paying attention to sudden thoughts &amp; emotions, and following the signs (questions and instincts) was enough to finally see what Im capable of.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/empath-101-learning-curve/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a8e2590c7630e2294972d84</guid><category>Empath</category><dc:creator>Ashley T.</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/7---Empath-101-2.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/02/7---Empath-101-2.jpg" alt="Empath 101 - Learning Curve"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, simply paying attention to sudden thoughts &amp;amp; emotions, and following the signs (questions and instincts) was enough to finally see what Im capable of. As I began to speak up more, not only did I find I was I getting reassurance on my suspicions, but also that those with personal issues would immediately open up to me. I naturally counsel as Ive already felt their mood and have some insight as to what it is and how to comfort/remedy it; following through with this action has given me further reassurance in my ability. With practicing all of this over time I suddenly realized that not only was I able to control it, I was also finally confident that I am my genuine self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If youre not sure how to do this, I can suggest a simple tactic thats taken right from my INFJ ways: question and investigate everything. As I did my initial research on what it is to be an empath, I started to sift through my life experiences and saw where others emotions and insights determined how I felt (about myself) because I didnt know better. One of the best ways that I now describe it is that I thought it was normal to know others thoughts and moods, but not knowing why/what that was caused me to suffer and turn in on myself for many years. So at first I started small, simply keeping to a small group of people I was comfortable with in which I could openly speak. Every time I had a thought or felt an emotion that didnt register as my own immediate focus or concern, I turned to whoever was in my surroundings and talked to them about it  there was rarely a time I wasnt able to determine what came from who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds forward and possibly a bit ridiculous (depending on your approach and who you have to work with, mostly), but I can assure you thats the best way to learn your capabilities for yourself and get affirmation. Having said all that though, there is a cautionary area (filter) that I did want to talk about. One too many times now, Ive dealt with a situation in which I was the recipient of life-altering news that (in all honesty) actually didnt surprise me and reaffirmed past suspicions. Obviously, I did not reveal any of my thoughts at any point in time; this can be a bit of a burden to carry when it involves those closest to you. The reason? We need to know when not to say something, simply because it would be so critical that actual evidence would be the only grounds to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part, I tend not to reveal these thoughts for more than that reason though: in a way, I also question the (current) validity of it. While time and time again I find most of my unwanted suspicions come true, I also hold onto that sliver of hope that circumstances could change and it wouldnt be true. Anyone that provides readings likely agrees with me on this: the sometimes over-looked fact is that no matter what answers we provide, theres always a chance that a split-second decision in a different direction can change the outcome (answer) completely.  Knowing this is true about everything in life, is the real reason why I hold back some of the worst thoughts that I have had. And lets not even get started on the fact of seeing things that could be, but arent acted upon!&lt;br&gt;
With all that being said, I mostly carry this filter with those I care for  unless, of course, their life is in danger. Anytime I have done a reading for someone (no matter their relationship to me), I allow my thoughts to be relayed as I hear them and I dont censor my final interpretation. I mention this because what Ive written above does not make sense if youre trying to make a reputable career doing such but may still apply in some parts of life. While not the same filter, I also have a method for when Im in crowded places such as the mall, busy stores, or a concert  without doing that, I would suffer the consequences of many people. This is your more important weapon, and is what most refer to as Protection or Grounding. There are many methods to be found online and it is something you can learn to do in your own style within a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest, and most important, things I learned for myself early on was to let go of everything I encounter. Carrying such thoughts (such as those unspeakable messages), and having such conversations can take a toll on our energy. Aside from solitude, I began practicing Etheric Cord Cleansing at the end of the day. If youre unfamiliar with this Cleansing, its very simple and is something that only needs a few minutes (you can find many examples online  theres no one right way; similar to Protection/Grounding). Regardless of what works best for you, the one thing you want to adapt to quickly is learning to listen to your body. Your body (usually) gives you the first indicator of anything thats wrong, but its our ability to recognize and react to it that results in the ultimate outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While important no matter who you are and why, listening to your body helps to add context and help you to get to know yourself. Aside from feeling the emotions and state of someone near you, your body has its own way of telling you what to do. Whether its your natural reaction to the truth of a persons thoughts or conversation, speaking the words that you feel and wonder if you should say, or simply your own need to seek safe space and time, your body gives you the indicators you need. After recognizing the cues and identifying them over a period of time, you will be able to develop (and likely even surprise) yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>